[MUSIC]
(音乐)
Stanford University,
斯坦福大学,
>> All right, well, welcome to Stanford CS193P,
> >好吧,好吧,欢迎来到斯坦福CS193P,
that's Developing Applications for iOS, winter of 2017,
这是iOS应用程序开发,2017年冬天,
So today, our topic is to talk about custom views, okay,
今天,我们的主题是讨论自定义视图,好吧,
specifically the drawing side of having custom views,
专门画的一面有自定义视图,
And this is gonna be a more typical lecture than last
这将是一个比去年更典型的讲座
time because I'll be doing some slides and
因为我会做一些幻灯片
explaining the concepts to you, and
对你解释的概念,
then I'll go into a demo that shows you how we do it all,
然后我会进入一个演示程序,展示了如何我们所做的一切,
So what is a view?
一个视图是什么?
A view is a subclass of UIView,
视图是UIView的子类,
which is in UIKit in iOS,
这是在iOS UIKit,
And all it does is carve out or
它所做的是开拓
represent a rectangular area on screen,
代表一个矩形区域在屏幕上,
And that rectangular area defines a coordinate space
矩形区域定义了一个坐标空间
that we're gonna draw in and that we're gonna get
我们要吸引我们
multi-touch events like pinches and
像捏和多点触摸事件
swipes and all that stuff,
啤酒和所有的东西,
So today,
所以今天,
I'm just gonna focus on the drawing side of that all and
我要关注所有和画的一面
then we'll start talking about the gestures on Wednesday,
然后我们开始讨论周三的手势,
So these views, these little rectangle areas
所以这些观点,这些小矩形区域
are put on screen in this hierarchical way,
提出在屏幕上在这个层次,
And that just means that the views have subviews
这就意味着视图的子视图
inside of them,
里面的
Now any given view can only have one superview,
现在任何给定的视图可以只有一个父视图,
that's the view that it's contained in,
中包含的视图,
But it can have any number of subviews,
但它可以拥有任意数量的子视图,
so views made out of it,
所以观点的,
So for example, on the calculator, we had for
举个例子,计算器,我们有
example, stack view, okay,
例子中,堆栈视图,
It had a lot of subviews,
它有很多的子视图,
all the buttons that we stacked in it,
我们堆在它所有的按钮,
In fact, some of the stack views had other stack views as
事实上,一些其他堆栈视图是堆栈的看法
their subviews,
他们的子视图,
And then those stack views had more subviews,
然后这些堆栈视图有更多的子视图,
which were buttons or whatever, okay,
按钮之类的,好吧,
So that's how we build our UI is this hierarchical
这就是我们构建UI是这个层次
collection of these rectangular areas,
这些矩形区域的集合,
Now, at the very, very, very top there's a special UIView
现在,非常,非常,非常有特殊UIView
called UIWindow class, we don't deal with that in iOS,
叫ui窗口类,我们不处理,在iOS,
In fact, the only time you would ever do anything with
事实上,唯一一次你会做任何事情
the UIWindow is if you were building an app that maybe
ui窗口是如果您正在构建一个应用程序,也许吧
projected to a projector,
将一个投影仪,
So that you had two screens, your device and
所以你有两个屏幕,你的设备
then maybe some external projector or
也许一些外部投影仪或
something, then you might care about UIWindow,
的东西,那么你可能关心的ui窗口,
But otherwise, it's all about UIView, okay?
但除此之外,都是关于UIView,好吗?
All of our arrangement of the screen is all about how we
我们所有的都是关于我们如何安排的屏幕
arrange the UIViews,
安排ui视图,
Now this hierarchy, okay, these rectangular areas inside
现在这个层次,这些矩形区域内
of rectangular areas, is almost always built
的矩形区域,几乎总是
in Interface Builder, inside Xcode, okay?
在界面构建器,Xcode,好吗?
That's how we built the stack view stuff,
这就是我们建立了堆栈视图的东西,
We dragged out a bunch of buttons and
我们拖出一串按钮和
then we selected them and said,
然后我们选择他们,说,
"Embed in Stack View," Well, that wrapped it in there,
“嵌入在堆栈视图中,“嗯,这包裹在里面,
But we can also build that hierarchy by dragging views
但我们也可以通过拖动视图建立层次结构
out of the utilities,
公用事业,
bottom of the utilities window there, inside other views,
工具窗口的底部,在其他视图,
So you can drag,
所以你可以拖拽,
do it by dragging-dropping inside of other views,
做dragging-dropping其他视图,
It is possible to do it in code but
但可以用代码
usually we're doing it graphically,
通常我们做得更生动,
If you're doing it in code,
如果你在代码中,
the two main methods involved in building and
参与建设和两个主要方法
destroying this hierarchy, are addSubview, okay,
摧毁这个层次,addSubview,好吧,
addSubview, takes a view as an argument,
addSubview,以一个视图作为参数,
You send it to the "soon-to-be" superview of that
你发送到“即将”父视图
In other words, you ask another view,
换句话说,你问另一个视图,
view,
看来,
please add this other view as subview of yourself,
请添加其他视图作为自己的子视图,
Now when you're doing the opposite, taking some view out
现在,当你在做相反的,一些观点
of the hierarchy, you don't send it to the superview,
层次结构的,你不将其发送到父视图,
You send it to the actual view itself,
你寄到实际视图本身,
basically remove yourself from this view hierarchy,
基本上把自己从这个视图层次结构,
So you send removeFromSuperview
所以你发送removeFromSuperview
to the actual view you want removed,
你想删除实际的观点,
Now where does this hierarchy start?
现在这个层次开始?
I guess you could say it starts in UIWindow,
我猜你可能会说它开始在ui窗口,
But for our purposes, we don't even pay attention to that,
但是对于我们的目的,我们甚至不注意,
It starts at the top level view
它开始在顶层视图
in that scene in Interface Builder,
在那个场景界面构建器,
The scene that's controlled by our view controller, right?
现场由视图控制器控制,对吧?
That rectangular area that we work in,
我们工作的矩形区域,
There's a top,
有一个,
top level view that covers the whole space up there,
顶级视图,覆盖整个空间,
And there is an important instance variable,
还有一个重要的实例变量,
property, in UIViewController,
属性,在ui中,
Okay, so all subclasses of UIViewController get
好的,那么所有子类的ui
this property,
这个属性,
It's called view and it's a UIView and a top level view,
它被称为视图和UIView和顶层视图,
And it's very important to understand that in an MVC,
和理解非常重要,在MVC中,
the controller has this, always has this var which
这个控制器,总是这var
points to the very top of that view hierarchy in its scene,
指出最顶端的视图层次的场景,
This top level view is important because for example,
例如,这个顶级视图是很重要的,因为
when you rotate, it's the thing whose bounds changes,
当你旋转时,它的范围的变化,
that top level view,
顶级视图,
And you're gonna learn a little later that when
你会晚些时候,当学习
the bounds of a view changes, there's a mechanism for
一个视图的范围的变化,有一个机制
offering all of its subviews an opportunity to change,
提供它的所有子视图一个改变的机会,
So that's why when we rotate device,
这就是为什么当我们旋转装置,
that top level view changes from being tall and
高,顶级视图变化
thin to being wide and less tall,
薄宽,不高,
And that causes all those stack views and
导致这些堆栈视图和
everything else to start getting resized as well,
一切开始调整大小,
because they're all subviews of this top level view, okay?
因为他们都是顶级视图的子视图,好吗?
If you were going to add views to the view hierarchy
如果你要添加视图的视图层次结构
programmatically rather than dragging and
通过编程而不是拖拽
dropping them, then you would need this view because it's
去掉它们,那么你需要这个观点,因为它是
the top of the entire view hierarchy,
整个视图层次,
And you would kinda work your way down
你会有点工作
to find out where you want to put that view,
找出你想要把这一观点,
But we don't otherwise actually look at this view
但我们不否则实际上看这个观点
much because we usually have outlets, rights?
因为我们通常有网点,权利?
IBOutlets--like the display that points to the label--that
iboutlet——比如,显示指向标签
gives us access to that label,
让我们进入标签,
That's all we want, so
这就是我们想要的,所以
we don't have to go looking at the top level view and
我们没有去看顶层视图和
looking all down the views, okay?
所有的视图看,好吗?
So this is important to know about but
知道,但这是重要的
surprisingly you don't access it that much, okay,
令人惊奇的是你不访问它,好吧,
This view is automatically hooked up for you in
这种观点是自动为您接通
Interface Builder when you drag out a View Controller,
界面构建器当你拖出一个视图控制器,
It's just all magically hooked up,
这只是所有神奇地连接,
you don't have to worry about that,
你不需要担心,
Okay, let's talk about initialization of the UIView,
好吧,让我们来谈谈UIView的初始化,
As usual, when you saw the lecture from last time,
像往常一样,当你看到上次的讲座,
you probably realize, whoa, initialization has a lot of
你可能意识到,哇,初始化有很多
caveats when you're talking about initializing a class,
说明当你谈论初始化一个类,
Remember all those rules I was going through?
我记得所有这些规则正在经历吗?
right?
对吧?
Required convenience and its inheritance, all this stuff,
需要方便和继承,所有这些东西,
So we try to avoid initializers generally as much
所以我们尽量避免初始化一般
as we can by doing all the things I talked
我们可以通过做我说的一切
about on Wednesday, like setting things equal or
周三,像设置相等或东西
even using lazy or something like that,
即使使用懒之类的,
But if you can't avoid it,
但是如果你无法避免,
UIView has an interesting initializer situation,
UIView初始值设定项的情况,非常有趣
It has two initializers that you have to deal with,
它有两个初始化处理,
Okay, one of them, init, with the frame is the argument, is
好吧,其中一个init,框架的论点是,
the one that you would call if you're trying to create a view
你所说的如果你想创建一个视图
in code, which you'll probably never do in this class, okay?
代码,你可能永远不会在这个类中,好吗?
Because you're always gonna use or
因为你总是会使用或
do it in Interface Builder with Xcode,
在Xcode界面构建器,
But, so that's the kind of in-code one,
但是,这是在代码中一个,
And init with this coder thing,
和初始化这个编码器,
which I'll talk about right at the end of class,
我年底会讨论正确的类,
but it's not important to know early on,
但这并不重要,
That's the init that gets called when your stuff come
这是你的东西的时候调用init
outs of Interface Builder, right?
接口生成器的输出,对吧?
When it comes from, when you built in Xcode,
当它来自,当你在Xcode中构建的,
All the stuff that you're building in Interface Builder
所有的东西你的建筑界面构建器
essentially gets coded,
基本上被编码,
that's what this coder business is about,
这就是这个编码器业务,
Gets coded into an XML file, kind of freeze dried,
被编码到一个XML文件,冷冻干燥,
And then when you run your program, that XML file gets
当你运行你的程序,XML文件
loaded in and it's kind of the instructions for
载入的指令
how to create all those objects, okay?
如何创建这些对象,好吗?
And init with coder is the initializer it uses
init和它所使用的编码器是初始值设定项
to recreate the view,
重新创建视图,
So if you have any code that needs to go in an initializer,
如果你有任何需要在一个初始化的代码,
like you need to initialize some var in your UIView,
喜欢你需要初始化一些UIView var,
you have to do it like this,
你必须这样做,
Override both of these inits,
覆盖这两个init,
one of them is a required init, the coder one,
其中一个是一个必需的init,编码器,
And we create some other method like this green setup
我们创建一些其他方法如这个绿色的设置
method I have,
我有方法,
And just call that method from both of them,
就从他们两人调用该方法,
That way you're guaranteed that whether your custom view
这样你保证无论你的自定义视图
is created in code or created in Interface Builder,
是在界面中创建的代码或Builder创建的,
it will get initialized properly,
它将正常初始化,
If you have vars that have to be initialized, you may not be
如果你有增值供应商必须初始化,你可能不是
able to use this mechanism of course because you can't
可以使用这种机制当然因为你不能
call methods in yourself until you're initialized,
调用方法自己直到你初始化,
So you might have to have that var initialization be
所以你可能需要变量初始化
somewhat duplicated there,
有些重复,
There's another alternative to initialization though and this
还有另一个选择初始化虽然这
is for any other object that comes out of Interface Builder
是任何其他对象,出来界面构建器吗
which is called awakeFromNib,
这叫做awakeFromNib,
Okay, awakeFromNib,
好的,awakeFromNib,
This is sent to every single object that ever comes out
这是发送到每一个对象,就出来了
of Interface Builder file, okay, that you edit
界面构建器文件,编辑
in the story board there including views and
在故事板包括视图和
your View Controller for that matter,
你的视图控制器,
And so
所以
the "Your object must be completely initialized,"
“你的对象必须是完全初始化”,
Those restrictions are not satisfied by this,
这些限制并不满意,
But still you can put code in there, you get, get going,
但仍然可以把代码放进去,你会得到,走了,
And we're gonna learn all kinds of ways to do
我们要学习各种各样的方法
initialization throughout our system down the road,
在我们的系统初始化,
but that's basically how you initialize UIViews,
但这基本上是如何初始化ui视图,
Okay so we're gonna talk now about UIView
所以我们会谈论现在UIView
as this rectangular area in which we're gonna draw,
这个我们要画矩形区域,
And so to do that we need talk about some types,
所以要做到这一点,我们需要谈论一些类型,
They're some very important types that you need to know,
它们是一些非常重要的类型,你需要知道,
One of them is CGFloat,
其中一个是CGFloat,
So CGFloat is a floating point value,
所以CGFloat是一个浮点值,
All of your coordinates that you're gonna be drawing in
你所有的坐标,你会被吸引
are all floating point values, but they're not doubles,
都是浮点值,但是它们不是双打,
they're not floats, they're CGFloats,
他们不漂浮,它们cgfloat,
So this is a type,
这是一个类型,
a real type that you have to use all the time
一个真正的类型,你必须使用所有的时间
when you're doing anything with the drawing, okay?
当你做任何图纸,好吗?
CG stands for Core Graphics,
CG代表核心图形,
this is the "graphics float" right here, okay?
这是“图形漂浮”在这里,好吗?
There's also a CGPoint which is just a struct with two
还有一个CGPoint,只是一个结构有两个
things in it, x and y, they're both CGFloats, CGPoint
事情,x和y,它们都是cgfloat CGPoint
represents a point in your coordinate system somewhere,
代表一个点的坐标系统,
Again, floating point coordinates,
再次,浮点坐标,
There's also CGSize, which represents an extent,
还有CGSize代表某种程度上,
You know, a width and a height, okay?
你知道,一个宽度和一个高度,好吗?
Only, it's just the struct, with two CGFloats, width and
只是,只是结构,两个cgfloat,宽度和
height, simple,
高度,简单,
And there's CGRect, of course, which is a rectangle,
CGRect中,当然,这是一个矩形,
It's a struct that has an origin, which is CGPoint, and
这个结构有一个起源,CGPoint,
an extent, which is a size,
某种程度上,这是一个尺寸,
So a rectangle represents a size, okay?
所以一个矩形代表一个尺寸,好吗?
So creating a CGRect--there's actually quite a few
所以创建CGRect中,实际上有不少
initializers for it,
初始化,
You can create an origin and size,
您可以创建一个起源和大小,
you can do an x y with height, things like that,
你可以做一个x y高度,类似这样的事情,
And CGRect also has a lot of really cool,
和CGRect中也有很多很酷的,
little convenience vars and funcs and thing like that,
小便利var和函数,这样的事情,
maxY, midY, those'll tell you thing like where's the left
maxY midY,这些像左边的会告诉你的事情
Like minX,
喜欢风骚女子,
edge of your rect to the top to the left or the bottom,
左边缘的矩形顶部或底部,
The middle points, etc,
中间点,等等,
There's also nice functions like intersects other rect
还有漂亮的功能像其他矩形相交
will return whether the two rectangles cross over,
将返回两个矩形是否跨越,
And there's even contains whether a point
,甚至还有包含一个点
is inside the rectangle, etc,
在矩形等,
So there's quite a few of these,
所以有不少,
I can't put them all on the slide, so
我不能把他们都在幻灯片上,
you're gonna wanna familiarize yourselves with CGRect,
你会想让自己熟悉CGRect中,
Because it probably has a lot of things in there that
因为它可能有很多东西
you would otherwise be writing your own code to do,
你本可以编写自己的代码,
Okay, so now that we have those types,
好了,现在我们有那些类型,
those four types, we can start talking about this coordinate
这四个类型,我们可以开始讨论这个坐标
system that we're gonna be doing our drawing in,
系统,我们会做我们的图画,
Now, the most important thing to understand,
现在,最重要的是要理解,
the simplest thing, is that the origin of this coordinate
最简单的是,这个坐标的起源
system is in the upper left of the screen,
系统是在屏幕的左上角,
It's not Cartesian coordinates which the origin would be in
这不是笛卡尔坐标原点的
the lower left of the screen because in Cartesian
屏幕左下方的因为在笛卡儿
coordinates increasing y means up, but
y坐标增加意味着,但是
in this coordinate system increasing y means going down,
在这个坐标系统增加y意味着向下,
down the screen, okay?
屏幕上,好吗?
So very important to understand that,
明白,非常重要,
So you can see that point I have up there, 500,35 that's
所以你可以看到这一点我有,500,35的
500 over and 35 down from the origin upper left, okay?
500,35从起源上离开,好吗?
Now, the units in here that we're drawing are points,
现在,我们单位在这里画点,
Okay, be very careful that you understand the unit
好的,非常小心,你理解
terminology here, okay?
术语在这里,好吗?
It's in points, not pixels,
点,不是像素,
A pixel is like the smallest possible little light
一个像素的最小的小灯
that can be turned on on your screen,
可以打开你的屏幕上,
Okay, now some devices have a lot of pixels
好了,现在有些设备有很多像素
per point--they're very dense,
每点——它们非常密集,
And that's really great, because if you're drawing
这是真正伟大的,因为如果你要画
smooth curves--like fonts are just
光滑的曲线,如字体只是
smooth curves being drawn--you don't get jaggy edges,
光滑的曲线被画,你不要参差不齐的边缘,
because there's so many tiny little points, okay?
因为有很多小点,好吗?
But we can't make it, so that we draw in the pixel space,
但是我们不能让它,这样我们画像素空间,
otherwise, on a very dense pixel screen,
否则,在一个非常密集的像素的屏幕,
our image would be really small,
我们的形象是非常小的,
And then, in an undense one, it'd be really big,
在一个undense,它会非常大,
because the pixels are really big,
因为像素是非常大的,
So we instead of drawing in pixels,
所以我们不是画在像素,
we draw in points, okay?
我们画点,好吗?
This is the same point by the way that is like the point
这是同一点的方式,就像这一点
size of a font,
字体大小,
A 12 point font, same word there, same point, okay?
12号字体,同一个词在同一点,好吗?
So, you can find out though how many pixels there are per
所以,你可以发现尽管有多少像素/
point, in other words how high resolution your screen is,
点,换句话说是多么高分辨率屏幕,
with this var in UIView called contentScaleFactor,
var在UIView称为contentScaleFactor,
It's a CGFloat, it's either gonna be one, two, or
CGFloat,要么是要一个,两个,或
three currently,
目前,三个
Like, the iPhone 7 Plus is three,
iPhone 7 + 3,
Three pixels per point in each direction,
三个像素每点每一个方向,
And the older like iPhone 4s maybe?
和老喜欢iPhone 4 s也许吗?
Maybe all the way back to the 4 would be one,
也许一路回到了4人,
Okay, some of the older iPads would be one,
好的,一些年长的ipad将是,
The newer iPads would be two,
新ipad将两个,
So, If you're doing anything where you have to pay
所以,如果你做任何事,你必须支付
Okay?
好吧?
attention to the number of pixels of points,
注意像素点的数量,
this is what you need,
这是你需要的,
Now the great thing is, most of the time you don't care
现在的好处是,大部分时间你不在乎
because when you're using iOS to draw with a font,
因为当你使用iOS画字体,
it's automatically gonna do super smooth turns, and
它的自动要做超级光滑,
you don't even have to know what the scale factor is,
你甚至不需要知道比例因子,
Even if you're just drawing an arc,
即使你只是画一条弧线,
it'll make sure you do as little jaggies as possible,
它会确保你尽可能少的锯齿,
So, you rarely have to know this,
所以,你很少需要知道这个,
But actually, wake up,
但实际上,醒醒,
You do need to know for assignment three, okay?
你需要知道作业三,好吗?
So assignment three, you will have to know this,
所以作业三个,你要知道,
Alright, now,
好了,现在,
The most important var in all of UIView is this one: bounds,
这是最重要的var UIView:边界,
And even in that really important var,
即使在非常重要的变量,
really what you care about is the size,
真的是你关心的是大小,
This is, in your drawing coordinate system,
这是在你的坐标系统,
the space you have to draw in,
你画的空间,
This is basically the size of your view in your own drawing
这基本上是视图的大小在自己的画
coordinate system,
坐标系统,
So any time you're doing any drawing and
所以任何时候你做任何图纸和
you wanna draw something that's as wide as your view,
你想要画的东西宽你的视图,
you're gonna use bounds,size,width here,
你会使用范围、大小、宽度,
And you're almost always gonna have your bounds' origin be
和你几乎总是会有界限的起源
(0, 0) so if you want put something in upper left you're
(0,0)如果你想要把东西放在左上角
gonna put it at (0, 0) or close to (0, 0),
要把它在(0,0)或接近(0,0),
So this rect, bounds,
这个矩形边界,
is describing the area have to draw in,
描述该地区吸引,
Now it's important because you obviously want to,
现在显然是很重要的,因为你想,
depending on your size, draw yourself appropriately,
根据你的大小,适当画自己,
And it's also important because there are two other
这也是很重要的,因为有两个
vars that often get confused by students with bounds, and
var,经常与界限,学生感到困惑的
which are quite different: that is frame and center,
这有很大的不同:框架和中心,
So frame and center have nothing to do
所以框架和中心无关
with where you're drawing, that's bounds,
你的画,范围,
Frame and center is where you are in your super view,
框架和中心是你在父视图,
So here's a picture of that frame and center,
这是框架和中心的照片,
So center is where your center is in your superview's
所以中心就是你的父视图的中心
coordinate system and frame is a rectangle that completely
坐标系统和框架是完全一个矩形
encases you in your superview's coordinate system,
包围你的父视图的坐标系统,
And you might think, well the size of my frame is gonna be
,你可能会想,我的帧的大小会
exactly the same size as my bounds size, right?
完全相同的大小作为我的范围大小,对吗?
And the answer is no, because views can be rotated,
答案是否定的,因为视图可以旋转,
And if you have ever rotated a view like this green one,
如果你曾经旋转视图喜欢这个绿色的,
Inside the code that's drawing in View B, its bounds just
代码画在视图内B,其界限
View B,
视图,
looks like a normal rectangle, the fact that it's rotated,
看起来像一个正常的矩形,它的旋转,
it doesn't even know it's rotated,
它甚至不知道它的旋转,
But if you look at the center of it, or if you look at
但如果你看看它的中心,或如果你看看
the frame that encloses it, look, it's not the same size,
包含它的框架,它不是相同的大小,
It has to be bigger because, to the superview, View A,
它必须是大的,因为父视图,视图,
It's bigger,
这是大,
View B kinda looks like a diamond, right?
视图B有点像一颗钻石,对吧?
So it has to be bigger,
所以它必须更大,
So the bottom line here, never use frame or center to draw,
这里的底线,不要使用框架或中心画,
Frame and center are only used to position you
框架和中心只是用于确定你的位置
in your super view,
在你的父视图,
Okay, you can use either one,
好的,你可以使用一个,
If you set the center, it'll move the frame,
如果你设置中心,它会移动的框架,
if you set the frame, it'll adjust the center, okay,
如果你设置的框架,它会调整中心,好吧,
They're tied together,
他们绑在一起,
Okay,
好吧,
How do we create views?
我们如何创建视图?
Okay, because I already told you we don't really use
好吧,因为我已经告诉过你我们真的不使用
the initializer, we don't, you know,
初始值设定项,我们没有,你知道,
create them in code very much,
在代码中创建它们,
What we usually do is we drag them out
我们通常做的是我们把他们拖出来
Okay?
好吧?
from the Object Palette in the bottom of the utilities window
从对象面板底部的工具窗口
in Interface Builder,
在界面构建器,
But if I built a custom view, Paul's view or
但是如果我建立了一个自定义视图,保罗的视图或
something, it's not going to be in the palette, okay,
东西,它不会在调色板,好吧,
Xcode didn't ship with my view in the palette,
Xcode没有船在面板与我的观点,
So instead, there's a generic view, just plain UIView, and
所以,有一个通用视图,UIView精彩,
you're gonna drag that in,
你会拖的,
But then, you're gonna inspect it using the top half of
但是,你要使用的上半部分检查它
the utilities pane on the right, right?
实用程序面板右边,对吗?
You're gonna inspect it and
你要检查它
change its class to not be UIView,
改变它的类不是UIView,
It's gonna be your subclass of UIView, so Paul view or
它会成为你的子类UIView,所以保罗视图或
whatever, okay?
无论如何,好吗?
And this is a very important step to remember,
记住这是一个非常重要的一步,
When you create a custom view and you drag it into your UI,
当你创建一个定制的视图,并将它拖进你的UI,
you have to change its class to be your custom class,
你必须改变它的类是您的自定义类,
And we'll see that in the demo, how it works,
在演示中,我们会看到,它是如何工作的,
When you create it in code, of course,
当然,当你在代码中创建它
you're just doing UIView(frame:),
你只是做UIView(框架:)
and you provide the frame, okay?
和你提供的框架,好吗?
And that frame, remember, what does it describe?
框架,请记住,它描述什么?
Describes where this view is gonna be in its super view
描述这一观点是在它的父视图
when it gets added, that's all the frame is doing, okay?
时补充说,所有的框架所做的,对吧?
And you can create it with UIView(), no arguments,
并与UIView(),您可以创建没有参数,
Then it will be zero width, zero height, and
那么它将是零宽度、零高度,和
it'll be at zero, zero, so you won't even see it, so,
它将为零,零,所以你甚至不会看到它,所以,
But you could come along later and
但是你可以过来之后
change its frame and/or its center to move it around,
改变它的帧和/或移动它的中心,
Here, it's a really quick example,
在这里,这是一个很简单的例子,
how to create a view in code,
如何在代码中创建一个视图,
I'm gonna create a UILabel,
我要创建一个标签,
UILabel is just a subclass of UIView,
UILabel只是UIView的子类,
And notice that on the second line there,
请注意,在第二行,
I'm just saying label = UILabel(frame:) of whatever,
我只是说标签= UILabel(框架:),
So I'm giving it this frame, 20, 20, 150, right?
所以我给它这个框架,20日20日,150年,对吧?
And then I'm setting the text to "Hello",
然后我设置文本“Hello”,
Well, if I was doing this code in a UIViewController,
好吧,如果我在做这些代码在ui中,
then I could put it at that top level view,
然后我可以把它顶级视图,
it'd look like that, view,addSubview, okay?
它看起来就像,查看、addSubview好吗?
And it would add the subview,
它会添加子视图,
Custom views, so why do I ever need a custom view?
自定义视图,所以为什么我需要一个自定义视图?
Either I need to do custom drawing or
我需要做自定义绘图或
I need to do custom multi-touch input, okay?
我需要做定制的多点触控输入,好吗?
Those are the reasons
这些都是原因
that you're gonna create a custom view,
你要创建一个定制的视图,
And so we're gonna focus on the drawing, and
所以我们要专注于画画,和
the drawing is very, very simple, okay?
这幅图非常简单,好吗?
There's this one method that's called draw,
这里有一个方法叫做画,
And it takes one argument, which is a rect,
它接受一个参数,即这是一个矩形,
For historical reasons, we sometimes call it drawrect,
由于历史原因,我们有时称之为绘制矩形,
but it's not actually called drawrect anymore,
但实际上这不是叫绘制矩形,
It's called draw, and the argument is called rect,
它叫做画,参数被称为矩形,
And this draw is gonna be sent to you by the system,
这画会被发送到你的系统,
It's sent to your UIView subclass,
发送到你UIView子类,
you override it, and it gets sent to you by the system when
你覆盖它,它被系统时寄给你
the system wants you to draw yourself,
系统要你自己画,
This is the only way you can draw in your view,
这是唯一的办法你可以画在你看来,
is to be asked by the system to draw,
系统要求的画,
There is no other way to draw in iOS,
没有其他方法在iOS画,
So what's that rectangle about?
所以,长方形是什么?
That rectangle is some sub-area in your bounds
矩形是一些区范围
that it wants you to draw,
它想要你画,
Now, that's a performance enhancement, because you can
现在,这是一个性能增强,因为你可以
ignore that and draw your whole view, if you'd like,
忽略,画你的整个看来,如果你想,
But like in your assignment three, you're probably gonna
但就像在作业三个,你可能会
wanna pay attention to this rectangle because
要注意这个矩形,因为
your assignment three's draw is gonna be pretty expensive,
作业三个画会很贵,
so you wanna draw as little as possible,
所以你想画尽可能小,
So that's what this draw is, very simple,
这就是这画是什么,很简单,
it's just called by the system, time for you to draw,
它只是由系统调用,你画,
It's the only way to draw,
这是唯一的方法,
So it's really, really easy to understand,
所以它是非常容易理解,
Never call this method, ever,
没有调用这个方法,,
If you ever call this method, it's wrong,
如果你调用这个方法,它是错误的,
The system calls this method,
系统调用此方法,
the system's the only one who calls this method,
系统的唯一一个调用此方法,
So what happens if you need to draw?
所以如果你需要画吗?
Something changed, and you wanna redraw,
一些改变,你想重绘,
You call one of these two methods, setNeedsDisplay or
你调用这两个方法之一,setNeedsDisplay或
setNeedsDisplay with the argument of a rect,
setNeedsDisplay矩形的论点,
And that's telling the system, hey, system,
告诉系统,嘿,系统,
my view needs to be redrawn,
我认为需要重绘,
Please ask me to redraw it,
请让我重新画一下,
And at some appropriate time in the future,
在未来的某个合适的时间,
it will ask you to redraw it,
它会让你重新画一下,
But it knows better than you when the best time to draw is,
但它知道比你画的最佳时间是,
believe me,
相信我,
And the rect that you can pass, that's just the rect
和矩形,可以通过,这是矩形
that's gonna be passed onto your draw,
将被传递到你的画,
So setNeedsDisplay with a rect is like an optimized
所以setNeedsDisplay矩形就像一个优化
setNeedsDisplay,
It's like, I need to be redrawn, but
这就像,我需要重绘,但是
only this part of me,
只有这一部分的我,
And you can send this to any UIView, say, redraw this view,
你可以发送任何UIView,说,重绘这种观点,
Usually, views send it to themselves though because
通常,因为观点寄给自己
they're the ones who know best when they need to be redrawn,
他们最了解的人当他们需要重绘,
okay?
好吧?
Alright,
好了,
So, how do I implement this drawrect,
所以,如何实现这个绘制矩形,
draw, draw with a CGRect argument guy?
画,画CGRect中论点的家伙?
And the answer is, you're gonna do it with paths,
答案是,你要做的路径,
You're gonna create paths, and then you're going to stroke
你要创建路径,然后你会中风
them and fill them to make shapes and things like that,
填补他们形状之类的东西,
And then you're also gonna use text and images,
然后你也会使用文本和图像,
So that's the primary way that you're going to draw
这是你画的主要方式
in there, okay?
在那里,好吗?
So we'll talk about text and images in a minute,
所以我们将讨论文本和图像,
Let's talk about the drawing with the paths first,
让我们谈谈这幅图的路径,
There's really two ways to do it,
有两种方法可以做到这一点,
One is, you can get what's called a context,
一个是,你可以得到所谓的背景下,
a drawing context, and I'll show you how to get it,
绘图上下文,我将向您展示如何得到它,
And then you can send messages to that context like, move to
然后你可以发送消息到上下文,搬到
this point, draw a line to here, add an arc over here,
这一点上,画一条线到这里,添加一个弧,
put some text over here, things like that, okay?
把一些文本,类似这样的事情,好吗?
Actually, the text we're gonna do in a different way,
实际上,文本我们要用不同的方式,
but, so that's one way,
但是,这是一种方法,
And then the other way is, you can create a path object,
另一种方法是,你可以创建一个路径对象,
okay, using UIBezierPath, and it's the same kind of thing,
好的,使用UIBezierPath,同样的东西,
But you're gonna create this object that you're gonna tell
但是你要创建这个对象,你会告诉
that object, okay, I want this path to be moving to here, and
对象,好吧,我想要搬到这里,这条路
then a line here, and then an arc over to here, okay?
一条线,然后一个弧到这里,好吗?
So you create this path, and
所以你创建这个路径
then you send a message to that path saying, okay,
然后你发送消息到这条路说,好吧,
stroke it,
中风,
So it's a subtle difference, but you'll see,
这是一个微妙的差异,但你会看到,
We're gonna focus mainly on the UIBezierPath way,
我们将重点放在UIBezierPath的方式,
because it's kind of a little simpler,
因为它更简单,
So let's understand the concepts here of
我们理解的概念
Core Graphics, that's what the CG is that you're seeing in
核心图形,这就是重心,你看到
all the places here,
这里所有的地方,
And the number one thing about Core Graphics is,
关于核心图形和一件事是,
we need a context,
我们需要一个背景下,
And that context might be a drawing context for on-screen,
这上下文可能对屏幕绘图上下文,
it might be a printing context if we're printing,
这可能是一个印刷环境如果我们印刷,
might be a context of drawing to an off-screen bitmap, etc,
可能是屏幕位图的背景图,等等,
The one you care about is obviously the context to
你关心的人显然是上下文
draw in your drawrect,
画在你绘制矩形,
And you get that by calling this function,
通过调用这个函数得到,
This is just a Swift function,
这只是一个迅速的功能,
it's not on a class or anything,
这不是在一个类或任何东西,
UIGraphicsGetCurrentContext(), and
UIGraphicsGetCurrentContext()和
that's going to get you a context that you can then
这将让你一个上下文,您可以
tell it to create a path by moving and all that stuff,
告诉它创建一个路径通过移动和所有的东西,
Which is what you do then, you create these paths out of
这是你做什么,你创建这些路径的
lines and arcs and things like that,
线和弧之类的东西,
Then you set drawing attributes in the context,
然后上下文中设置绘图属性,
like the colors you wanna use, the fonts if you're doing
您想要使用的颜色,字体,如果你正在做的事情
text, line widths, those kinds of things,
文本、线宽、这些东西,
You set those all up, and then you stroke and fill,
你设置这些,然后你中风和填补,
And that's it, stroking and
就是这样,抚摸着
filling are actually the only two directives that actually
填充实际上是唯一两个指令
cause something to happen on screen,
导致事情发生在屏幕上,
But keep in mind that, like,
但是要记住,
a font is basically just a really exquisite path filled,
字体基本上就是一个很精致的路径,
okay, or stroked and filled,
好的,或描边和填充,
So you can do a lot with stroking and filling,
所以你可以做很多抚摸和填充,
So UIBezierPath kinda encapsulates all of those
所以UIBezierPath封装了所有这些
Core Graphics concepts into an object,
核心图形概念转化为一个对象,
And so I have an example here to show you how I would use
所以我在这里有一个例子展示如何使用
UIBezierPath to draw a triangle on screen,
UIBezierPath在屏幕上画一个三角形,
First, I'm gonna create the path by just saying,
首先,我要创建的路径只是说,
path = UIBezierPath(),
路径= UIBezierPath(),
There are other initializers for it,
还有其他的初始化,
which we'll see in the demo,
在演示中,我们会看到
But this one just creates a blank path to start,
但是这个只是创建一个空白的路径开始,
Then, you move around with the path,
然后,你移动的路径,
So like I can say, move to, which (80,
所以我可以说,移动到(80年
50) is like halfway across this, this little screen,
50)就像在这一半,这个小屏幕,
This is small screen, let's say, 160 points wide,
这是小屏幕,比方说,160点宽,
80 and then 50 down, okay?
80,然后下来,好吗?
Then I'm gonna add a line down to 140, 50, see that, okay?
然后我要添加一行到140年,50岁,看到,好吗?
Then I'm gonna add another line over to 10,
然后我要添加另一行到10,
off to the left, I'm still 150 down,
离开,我还150,
Then I'm gonna close the path, okay, using close, and
然后我要关闭的路径,使用,和
that just closes it back to the start,
关闭它回到开始,
So look, I made a triangle, okay, really easy,
看,我做了一个三角形,很简单,
Now, the only thing is, all this code right here would
现在,唯一的问题是,所有这些代码在这里
actually draw, instead of that triangle right there,
画,而不是三角形,
would draw this: nothing,
会画:没有,
You would see no drawing with that code because we haven't
你会看到没有绘图代码,因为我们还没有
stroked or filled it,
抚摸或填充它,
The stroking and filling is what draws,
抚摸和填充是什么了,
So how do we do the stroking and fill?
那么我们如何抚摸并填写吗?
Well, we need to set the colors that we wanna fill and
嗯,我们需要设置颜色,我们想要填补
stroke with,
中风,
But here, I'm taking green and
但在这里,我要带绿色和
sending it the message setFill,
发送消息setFill,
So you actually set your color to fill with
所以你设置你的颜色填充
by sending a message to a color,
发送消息到一个颜色,
You get a color, and you send it a message,
你会得到一个颜色,你发送消息,
set that as my fill color,
集,作为我的填充颜色,
And the same thing with a stroke,
和一样的中风,
set it as a stroke color,
把它作为一个中风的颜色,
So I set my stroke color to red, my fill color to green,
所以我我中风的颜色设置为红色,绿色填充色,
But when I'm talking about attributes like line width,
但当我谈论属性和线宽一样,
I send that to the path, to the UIBezierPath,
我发送路径,UIBezierPath,
Set your line width to three, okay, so I do that,
设置线宽三,所以我这样做,
Now, if I say path,fill, now I get a green triangle,
现在,如果我说路径,填满,现在我得到了一个绿色的三角形,
Because my fill color was green,
因为我的填充色是绿色,
and it takes that path and it fills it in,
和需要这条道路充满,
That's what fill does,
这是什么填满,
And similarly, if I say path,stroke,
同样的,如果我说路径,中风,
I get a red line around,
我得到一个红线,
Because the path that I took to get around there gets
因为我走上的路绕过
stroked with a three-point wide red line,
抚摸着三分宽的红线,
So that's it, that's quite simple actually,
就是这样,其实很简单,
That's how we draw,
这就是我们,
And, UIBezierPath also knows how to draw a lot of common
UIBezierPath也知道如何画很多共同之处
Okay?
好吧?
shapes, like rounded rectangles, and ovals, and
形状,像圆角矩形,椭圆形,
things like that, so you should familiarize yourself
类似这样的事情,所以你应该熟悉
with UIBezierPath's API, of course,
当然,与UIBezierPath API
Another cool thing you can do with UIBezierPath is you
另一个很酷的事情你可以做UIBezierPath是你
create a path like that triangle, and
创建一个路径这样的三角形,
you can clip all your drawings to that path,
你可以夹你所有的图纸路径,
So you could draw this elaborate picture that only
所以你可以画出这个精心设计的,只有图片
show the part that shows through that triangle,
显示部分显示通过三角形,
if you take that triangle path that we just created and
如果你把我们刚刚创建的那个三角形路径
say add clip to it,
说添加视频,
Because after that,
因为在那之后,
all drawing is only gonna show up inside that triangle,
所有图纸是只会出现在一个三角形,
you can make some pretty cool effects by doing it,
你可以通过做一些很酷的效果,
which is kinda cool,
这是有点酷,
The UIBezierPath also knows how to,
UIBezierPath也知道如何,
it has this method contains that will,
该方法包含,将
tell you whether a point is inside the path,
告诉你一个点是否在路径,
So that's good if you want to do some touch thing or people
这很好如果你想做一些联系的事情或人
are touching on something and you wanna do hit detection,
接触的东西和你想做检测,
basically, what they're touching on,
基本上,他们接触,
All right, and there's tons of other stuff in UIBezierPath,
好吧,还有在UIBezierPath吨其他东西,
don't have time to cover it, you should look it up,
没有时间去覆盖它,你应该查一下,
Okay, UIColor,
用户界面颜色,
So UIColor, really simple,
所以用户界面颜色,很简单的,
Okay, there's some common colors like green, red,
好的,还有一些常见的颜色如绿色、红色,
yellow, purple,
黄色,紫色,
Those have type methods on UIColor,
这些用户界面颜色类型方法,
Remember, type methods, static methods?
记住,类型方法,静态方法?
They're on the type,
他们的类型,
You don't need an instance of it,
你不需要它的一个实例,
So that's like UIColor,green,
这就像用户界面颜色,绿色,
But there's also initializers that let you create colors
但是也有让你创建的初始值设定项的颜色
from RGB, red, green, blue, or HSB, that's hue, saturation,
从RGB,红色,绿色,蓝色,或HSB,色调,饱和度,
You can even create a color that's made from a pattern,
你甚至可以创建一个颜色,是由一种模式,
brightness,
亮度,
So that when you draw with that color,
所以,当你画的颜色,
it's drawing in a pattern,
它的绘画模式,
Okay, like a really thick line,
好吧,像一个很粗的线,
we'd actually be showing the details of a pattern,
我们实际上是显示一个模式的细节,
which is kind of fun, using UIImage,
这是一种乐趣,使用用户界面图像,
which I'll talk about in a little bit,
我会讲一点,
Of course, all UIViews have a background color,
当然,所有ui视图有一个背景颜色,
We saw this when we did our buttons in the calculator,
我们看到这个时候我们在计算器的按钮,
we made the background color
我们做了背景颜色
of a lot of our buttons be light gray, and I'm sure in
我们的很多按钮是浅灰色的,我相信
the homework assignments you made it other colors,
作业你做其他颜色,
Okay, that's just a var on UIView,
好吧,这只是一个var UIView,
that button inherited from UIView,
按钮从UIView继承,
And you can set it to any UIColor you want,
你可以将它设置为任何用户界面颜色你想要的,
Now, an interesting thing about colors though is that
现在,关于颜色虽然是一件有趣的事
they can be transparent, or even semi-transparent, okay?
他们可以是透明的,甚至是半透明的,好吗?
And they are done, you specify that with alpha,
他们完成,您指定,在α,
How many people here know what alpha
这里有多少人知道α
is when it comes to graphics?
当涉及到图形吗?
Okay, so hardly anybody,
几乎没有人,
So alpha is just a value between 0 and 1, where 0 means
所以α是一个值在0和1之间,0表示
fully transparent and 1 is fully opaque,
完全透明,1是完全不透明,
So if you have a color like a triangle and
如果你有一个颜色像一个三角形
you fill it with green, then if it's fully opaque,
然后绿色,如果完全不透明,
you can't see anything behind that triangle,
你后面什么也看不见,三角形,
But if it were 50%, 0,5 alpha,
但如果是50%,0,5α,
then you'd be able to see the green but
然后你可以看到绿色的
you'd also be able to see the things behind it a little bit,
你也可以看一下后面的事情,
50% kinda, okay?
50%一点,好吗?
If it was zero, you wouldn't see any
如果是零,你不会看到任何
green because it would be fully transparent,
绿色,因为它是完全透明,
You'd be looking all the way through it, so
你会看到所有的方式通过,
you wouldn't see any green, okay?
你不会看到任何绿色,好吗?
So, all that you can put anywhere in that range, and
所以,你可以把任何范围,和
the way you create a transparent color is by taking
你创建一个透明的颜色是通过
a opaque color and saying, withAlphaComponent,
一个不透明的颜色和说,withAlphaComponent,
whatever alpha you want between 0 and 1,
任何你想要的alpha值在0和1之间,
Okay? And that gives you
好吧?
a transparent or
一个透明的或
semi-transparent version of the color,
半透明的颜色,
And you can draw with that,
你可以画,
However, if you draw with transparency in your UIView,
但是,如果你用透明度画在你这里,
you must set this var on your UIView,
你必须设置这个var UIView,
This is just a var in UIView to false,
这只是一个var UIView虚假,
Okay? Because views assume that
好吧?
they're fully opaque, okay?
他们完全不透明,好吗?
And that's performance enhancement,
性能增强,
It turns out drawing with transparency,
原来图纸与透明度,
as you might imagine, takes a little bit of CPU power
你可能会想象,需要一点点的CPU
to figure out which pixels show through and all that,
找出哪些像素显示通过,
So, by default, it assumes you're drawing fully opaque,
所以,默认情况下,它假定你要画完全不透明,
So if you wanna draw with transparency,
所以如果你想画与透明度,
don't forget to set opaque here to false,
不要忘记设置不透明的假,
By the way, you can make your entire view semi-transparent
顺便说一下,你可以让你的整个视图半透明
by setting its alpha,
通过设置其α,
So this is a var, not in color,
这是一个var,不是彩色的,
this is a var in UIView,
这是一个var在这里,
You can say, alpha 0,5,
你可以说,α0、5、
in your entire view will be 50% see-through,
在整个视图将50%透明,
And that would work with a button or
这将使用一个按钮或
anything because those are just UIViews,
因为这些只是ui视图,
Alright?
对吧?
What happens when views overlap and
当重叠和看法
we have transparency in the views?
我们有透明度的观点吗?
Well, then that subviews that we're talking about,
好吧,那我们讨论的子视图,
all the subviews of a view starts to matter in the order,
所有视图的子视图开始的顺序,
So the first thing in the subview,
首先在子视图,
subview sub zero, that's all the way in the back,
子视图的子零,一直在后面,
And then everything else is in the order in front of
然后其他的都是在前面的订单
it, okay?
它,好吗?
And so, any transparency that's going on is things
因此,任何是事情的透明度
stacked up in that order, and you're looking down through
叠加的顺序,你往下看
the transparency, all the way up to subview zero,
透明,一直到子视图为零,
so which is in the back, okay?
所以在后面,好吗?
You can also completely hide a view,
你也可以完全隐藏一个视图,
This is very similar--almost identical to--saying
这是非常相似的,几乎一模一样,说
alpha equals zero,
α= 0,
Which will just make the view not even appear, but
这只会让视图甚至不出现,但
it will be still in the view hierarchy,
它仍然会在视图层次,
It will be still in its superview and
它仍然会在父视图和
its subviews will still be subviews of it, but
它的子视图仍将子视图,但是
it all will be completely hidden,
这一切将完全隐藏,
And why would you wanna do this?
为什么你会想这样做吗?
Maybe you have some UI where you don't wanna show a button
也许你有一些UI,你不想显示一个按钮
until the user has entered some other field or
直到用户已进入其他领域或
something like that,
类似的,
But you wanna make room for the button,
但是你想让房间的按钮,
You want it to be ready to appear, so
你想要准备出现,
you leave it in the view hierarchy, but hidden,
你把它在视图层次,但隐藏,
Okay? Alright,
好吧?
let's talk about drawing text,
让我们来谈谈画文本,
How do we draw text?
我们如何绘制文本?
Well, one way to draw text you already know is UILabel,
嗯,绘制文本你已经知道的一种方法是UILabel,
You could just create a UILabel and make it a subview
你可以创建一个标签和子视图
of your view and bingo, you got some text in your view,
你的视图和宾果,在你看来,你有一些文本
And now, the only problem with that is,
现在,唯一的问题是,
you're drawing in your draw, your drawRect thing,
你在你的画图纸,绘制矩形,
you're drawing in there,
你要画,
And you have to make sure you drew, if you're drawing around
你必须确保你了,如果你要画
the text that it all lined up with your subviews,
排列的文本,它与你的子视图,
So sometimes you wanna draw in drawRect, right?
所以有时你想画绘制矩形,对吧?
You want to actually draw in there,
你想画,
And the way you do that is with a class called
你这样做的方法是用一个类调用
NSAttributedString, okay?
NSAttributedString,好吗?
So NSAttributedString is not a string,
所以NSAttributedString不是一个字符串,
It's not related in any way actually to string, and
实际上它不是以任何方式相关的字符串,和
it's not even an NSString which is the old Objective-C
它甚至不是NSString老objective - c
style string that was indexed by ints where
风格字符串索引的整数
the Swift's one is indexed by string,index, unfortunately,
斯威夫特的一个由字符串索引,索引,不幸的是,
It's neither of those, it's its own thing,
它既不是的,它是自己的事情,
Okay?
好吧?
It's very closely aligned to old NSString,
它非常老NSString紧密地结合起来,
not as closely aligned to the modern string,
不像现代的字符串,紧密地结合起来,
But anyway, what an attributed string is it's a string,
但无论如何,一个带属性字符串是一个字符串,
you can make it out of a string or an NSString,
你可以让它一个字符串或一个NSString,
And those characters have attributes, colors and
和这些人物属性,和颜色
fonts and things like that, okay?
字体之类的东西,好吗?
And it's very simple,
这是很简单的,
you create one of these strings and
您创建一个字符串
you just send it to message draw at and it will draw
你只寄给消息画在画
that string at that point at its upper left corner,
该字符串在左上角,
Then you can even find out the size it's going to need to
你甚至可以找到需要的大小
Okay?
好吧?
draw it by sending the message size to an attributed string,
画通过发送消息大小的字符串,
Okay? Now one thing that's
好吧?
kind of bummer about attributed string,
对带属性字符串的游手好闲的人,
it's really an old style API,
这是一个老式API,
var and let don't even work to make it mutable or not,
var,让甚至不工作,让它可变,
So if you want a mutable attributed string, attributed
所以,如果你想要一个可变的字符串,由
string where you're gonna change its attributes and
你会改变它的属性和字符串
change its text, you need to have a different class called
改变它的文本,你需要有一个不同的类
NSMutableAttributedString,
So things like set attributes, and things of that,
所以设置属性,和事情,
don't work on an attributed string,
不工作在一个字符串,
You have a mutable attributed string,
你有一个可变的字符串,
Now, you can, if you have an attributed string, mutable or
现在,你可以,如果你有一个字符串,可变或
not, you can get back the string that's in it
不,你可以返回的字符串
as a string object using the var string, or
作为一个字符串对象使用var字符串,或
mutable string in a mutable case,
可变的字符串在一个可变的情况下,
That's kinda confusing because,
这有点让人困惑,因为
of course, you're used to var and let being how a string is
当然,你使用var,让被一个字符串
mutable or not, but that's how you can get the string back,
可变的,但这就是你可以得到字符串,
But let's talk about how you set the attributes,
但让我们来谈谈你如何设置属性,
So you set the attributes just by passing in this dictionary,
所以你设置属性只是通过在这本字典,
called attributes there,
称为属性,
You can either set attributes or add attributes to what's
你可以设置属性或属性添加到什么
already there, and this dictionary, String:Any,
已经有这本字典,字符串:任何,
the string is just a key like this is telling you what
字符串只是一个像这样的关键是告诉你什么
the attribute is, like it's a font, or a color, or whatever,
属性,如字体,或者颜色,等等,
And then the Any is,
然后是,
it might be a font, it might be a color,
这可能是一个字体,这可能是一个颜色,
depends on what the key is, that's why it's an Any there,
取决于什么是关键,这就是为什么它是一个任何,
because it can be all kinds of things,
因为它可以被各种各样的东西,
And really important to notice here is the range,
和非常重要的注意范围,
You see that range?
你看到这个范围吗?
It's not range that I talked to you on Wednesday,
这不是范围周三,我和你,
it's NSRange,
NSRange,
NSRange is an integer indexed range into that string,
NSRange是整数索引范围到字符串,
that attributed string,
由于字符串,
Old style integer, not string,index,
旧式的整数,而不是字符串,指数,
So this makes for a lot of trouble when you're using
这使得很多麻烦当你使用
attributed string in the Swift world,
由于字符串在迅速的世界里,
And my recommendation to you is that you use this method or
和我给你的建议是,你使用这种方法
this var rather on String called utf16,
这对字符串称为utf16 var,而,
utf16 will give you back what's called
utf16会给你所谓的
a String,UTF16View,
一个字符串,UTF16View,
That is a collection of the characters, it's not really
这是一个字符的集合,它不是真的
a collection like characters is, but it is a representation
一个像字符集合,但它是一个表示
of the string as distinct 16-bit Unicode characters,
不同的16位Unicode字符的字符串,
Which is much more aligned, in fact I think it's exactly
更一致,事实上我认为这是到底是什么
aligned, to what NSString does,
什么NSString对齐,
The only problem is, that thing that it gets,
唯一的问题是,那个东西,
that comes back, is still indexed by String,Index,
回来,仍由字符串索引,索引,
So you have to say what's the startIndex, offset by five,
所以你必须说什么startIndex,五所抵消,
that kind of business to move around in there,
这种业务移动,
And plus, you can't pass a range of String,Index into
再加上,你不能通过一系列字符串,指数
this setAttribute,
这个setAttribute,
So you have to kinda convert from String,Index,
所以你必须从字符串转换,指数,
how much you've advanced over,
你先进多少,
to an integer when you make these NSRanges,
这些nsrange整数时,
So, I'm sorry to say it's difficult,
所以,对不起,说它是困难的,
I'm not gonna actually ask you to do that,
实际上我不会问你,
this in the homework,
这个作业,
Partially because it, it's kind of a pain in the neck,
部分因为它,这是一种痛苦的脖子,
And I don't want you to spend your valuable homework
我不想让你花你宝贵的功课
time working on it,
工作时间,
But just know, if you start using this,
但如果你开始使用这才知道,
that you're gonna have this unfortunate disconnect,
你要有这个不幸的脱节,
And I keep hoping every time iOS comes out,
我一直希望每次iOS出来,
they'll come out with an attributed string, not NS, but
他们会推出一个字符串,NS,但是
attributed string, that's matched up with string,
由于字符串,匹配字符串,
But they haven't done it yet,
但是他们还没有做过,
It's pretty complicated to do, I can imagine, so,
很复杂,我可以想象,所以,
So what are some of these attributes that you can set?
那么其中的一些属性,您可以设置吗?
So there's things like NSForegroundColorAttributeN-
所以有NSForegroundColorAttributeN——之类的东西
ame, that's how you set the color of the text,
ame,如何设置文本的颜色,
There's also NSBackgroundColorAttributeName
还有NSBackgroundColorAttributeName
which, fonts have foregrounds and backgrounds, but
字体有前景和背景,但
don't worry about that too much,
不要担心太多,
NSStrokeWidth so
NSStrokeWidth所以
you can draw your characters really thick or thin,
你能画人物很厚或薄,
NSFontAttributeName, where you can provide a font,
NSFontAttributeName,你可以提供一个字体,
And there's about 15 others,
大约有15人,
and you can go look in the documentation for all of them,
你可以去看他们的文档,
But speaking of fonts,
但说到字体,
if you wanna set the font you're gonna draw with,
如果你想设置的字体你会画,
how do you do that?
你怎么做呢?
Well, fonts are super important in iOS,
嗯,在iOS字体非常重要,
Never underestimate the power of a font in building
永远不要低估一个字体在建设
a cool UI,
a,cool:
Look at all these UIs,
看看这些ui,
Look at how important the choice of font, size,
看看有多重要的选择字体,大小,
position, all that stuff is,
的位置,所有的东西,
So, how do we get a good font so that our UI will look good?
那么,我们如何得到一个好的字体,这样我们的UI就好看吗?
Well, we're gonna use this very important static
我们将使用这个非常重要的静态
method in UIFont,
方法在UIFont,
So you send this to UIFont, the class,
所以你把这UIFont类,
called preferredFont forTextStyle, okay?
叫preferredFont forTextStyle,好吗?
And so you can specify the text style, which is kind of
所以你可以指定文本样式,这是什么样的
like, what's the environment you're gonna use this text,
喜欢,是什么环境你会使用这个文本,
what kinda text is it?
有点什么文本?
And so there's about eight or so of them,
其中有8个左右,
But three of them are like a headline,
但三个人就像一个标题,
This is gonna be a headline,
这是一个标题,
So that's gonna be a bolder font, a little larger maybe,
这是将是一个更大胆的字体,有点大,
Then body font, that's like, this is the user's data,
身体的字体,就像,这是用户的数据,
So in a Mail message,
所以在一条邮件消息,
this would be the message they're actually typing
这将是他们实际上输入的消息
maybe--although it's probably a multi-font,
也许——尽管这可能是一个字体,
But, and then footnote would just be a small little text,
但是,然后脚注会只是一个小的文本,
you see, from the bottom?
你看,从底部?
So I really encourage you when you're using a font,
所以我鼓励你当你使用一个字体,
try to find a text style that will work, okay?
试图找到一个文本样式,将工作,好吗?
Because it's gonna be in sync and
因为它会和同步
compatible with all the other apps,
兼容所有其他应用程序,
because they're using these preferred fonts,
因为他们使用这些首选的字体,
And also, by the way, if a user goes in Settings and
而且,顺便说一下,如果用户设置和
sets their font size to be really large,
他们的字体大小设置为非常大,
these will automatically get larger, okay?
这些会自动变大,好吗?
And, hopefully, if you have your Auto-Layout working,
希望,如果你有自动布局工作,
everything will expand or contract properly, okay?
一切都会正常扩展或收缩,好吗?
There's also system fonts,
还有系统字体,
Don't get confused between the preferred fonts and
不喜欢字体和之间的混淆
system fonts,
系统字体,
Preferred fonts are for the user's content,
首选字体是用户的内容,
So, that's the difference there,
所以,这就是区别,
Now, most of this stuff, again,
现在,大部分的这些东西,
you're not even gonna set in code,
你没有在代码中设置,
You're gonna set it in Interface Builder in
你会在界面构建器
the little Inspector window, right?
小Inspector窗口,对吧?
You're gonna be setting, both preferred fonts and
你要设置,都喜欢的字体和
system fonts can be set there,
系统可以设置字体,
If you wanna use a specific font like Helvetica Bold 13
如果你想使用一个特定的字体像Helvetica粗体13
point, you can do that,
点,你能做到这一点,
I don't recommend it,
我不推荐它,
but UIFontDescriptor is an important class to know
但UIFontDescriptor是一个重要的类
It's how you describe that font that you want,
你如何描述的字体,你想要的,
for that,
为此,
that special font,
特殊的字体,
So, you know, some apps, typography is what they do,
所以,你知道,一些应用程序排版就是他们做的,
And so they need to be able to do specific fonts,
所以他们需要做特定的字体,
Alright, so that's text,
好了,这就是文本,
How about drawing images?
绘制图像怎么样?
So images, again, you, we have a thing like UILabel,
所以图片,再一次,你,我们有一件事像UILabel,
It's called UIImageView,
它叫做UIImageView,
And you could just make an image be a subview of
你可以做一个图像的子视图
your view if you wanted to have an image in there,
你认为如果你想要一个图像,
But, again, sometimes you wanna be able to control that
但是,有时你想控制
in your draw, your drawRect,
在你的画,你的绘制矩形,
And we do that with the UIImage object, okay?
我们可以用界面图像对象,好吗?
I already showed you actually when I was talking about
我已经给你当我在说什么
failable initializers how to create a UIImage,
failable初始值设定项如何创建一个用户界面图像,
You just put it in your xcassets file
你只要把它放在您的xcassets文件
in Interface Builder,
在界面构建器,
And then you say UIImage named, and it gets it by name,
然后你说界面图像命名,得到它的名字,
And if it can't find it, it returns nil,
如果它找不到,它返回nil,
So that's the number one way you're gonna get an image into
这是第一个方法你会得到一个图像
your app is put it in xcassets,
你的应用程序在xcassets所说,
But there are other ways to do it,
但还有其他的方法去做,
You can get it from a file, like if you had a ,jpg file,
你可以把它从一个文件,如果你有一个,jpg文件,
Of course, I haven't shown you how to get files,
当然,我还没有向您展示了如何获取文件,
So you don't know how to do that yet,
所以你不知道怎么做,
But, you can do it that way,
但是,你可以这样做,
And you can also get it just from raw data, raw jpg data or
你也可以把它从原始数据,原始数据或jpg格式
something that you got over the Internet or from a URL or
你在互联网上或从一个URL或
something, you can do that,
什么,你可以这样做,
You can even do it by drawing with all those path things,
你甚至可以做它与这些路径通过的事情,
You can use this UIGraphicsBeginImageContext
您可以使用此UIGraphicsBeginImageContext
for a certain size region,
一定规模的地区,
And then you can just use UIBezierpath draw or
然后您可以使用UIBezierpath画或
get graphics context, whatever, draw in there,
得到图形上下文,无论如何,画在里面,
And then there's an EndImageContext,
然后有一个EndImageContext,
And it'll capture it and create a little image for you,
和它会捕获它,为你创建一个图像,
So that's another way to do it,
这是另一种方式去做,
So once you have an image, okay, that you got from any of
一旦你有一个图片,你从任何
these sources, you can just draw it inside your drawRect
这些来源,你可以把它画在绘制矩形
by saying draw atPoint or draw inRect,
说画atPoint或者画inRect,
Or actually, I think that's probably drawAt space point,
或者,我认为可能是drawAt空间点,
not atPoint:,
不是atPoint:,
And drawIn space rect and drawAsPatternIn space rect,
和港湾式停车站空间矩形和drawAsPatternIn空间矩形,
Those do kind of what you would think, right?
你会认为,对吧?
draw atPoint draws it where that's the upper left hand
画atPoint吸引地方上的左手
corner, it draws it in its natural size,
角落里,它吸引了在它的自然大小,
draw inRect is going to scale it to fit inside
画inRect里面适合规模
the rectangle that you provide,
您提供的矩形,
And drawAsPattern is gonna tile it,
drawAsPattern将瓷砖,
So presumably that's a small image and
所以大概一个小图像
you're drawing a texture or something,
你要画一个纹理之类的,
And it's gonna repeat it over and
和它会重复一遍
over to fill the rectangle, okay?
在填充矩形,好吗?
I'll fix this slide and repost it,
我会解决这张幻灯片并转发,
Alright, one thing to be careful of with UIView,
好吧,一件事与UIView小心,
When UIView changes size,
当UIView改变大小,
you do not get asked to redraw by default,
你不要要求重绘在默认情况下,
What it does is, believe it or
它是什么,相信它
not, takes what you've drawn, grabs the pixels, and
不需要你了,抓住了像素,和
stretches them to fit the new bounds,
伸展以适应新的边界,
Okay, now, this is often not what you want,
好了,现在,这往往不是你想要的,
Often, what you want is, okay, if my bounds change,
通常情况下,你想要的是,如果我的变化范围,
ask me to redraw again in my new bounds, okay?
问我再次重画在我的新边界,好吗?
So how is this controlled?
这是如何控制的?
It's controlled via this var in UIView called contentMode,
通过控制这var在UIView称为内容模式,
And the contentMode can be things like left, right, top,
和内容模式可以像左,右,前,
bottom, topRight, topLeft,
底,topRight topLeft,
That's basically saying, take my bits and
基本上说,把我的比特和
shove them up into the left corner you know,
你知道的,把他们分成左角落
one of these spots, center or right,
其中的一个点,中心或吧,
Don't touch, don't do anything with them,
不联系,不做任何事情,
just move them in the new bounds,
就在新边界移动它们,
Well, that's likely to cut off what you've drawn or something
这可能会切断你画什么的
like that depending on how much the bounds have changed,
这样根据边界改变了多少,
Like when you rotate, you know,
就像当你旋转,你知道,
the bounds changes quite a bit,
范围变化很大,
There's also the scaling ones,
也有比例的,
And this is the default, scaleToFill,
这是默认,scaleToFill
And that says, take my bits and take my new bounds and
说,让我把我的新边界,
scale it to fill,
规模来填补,
I can preserve the aspect ratio if I want,
如果我想要的,我可以保持长宽比
Although, again,
不过,这一次
that's probably gonna cut something off,
这可能会减少一些,
But the real one that you want is redraw,
但真正的你想要的是重绘,
If you set your contentMode to be ,redraw,
如果你设置你的内容模式,重绘,
then when your bounds change, your draw is gonna be
当你的范围的变化,你会画
called--your drawRect, draw with the rect argument,
叫——你绘制矩形、画矩形参数,
So in your assignment three, you're gonna wanna do this,
所以在作业三个,你要想做到这一点,
You can actually do this,
你可以这样做,
you can do it in code by setting that var,
你可以在代码中通过设置变量,
But you can also do it in Interface Builder, okay?
但是你也可以在Interface Builder中这样做,好吗?
In the Utilities window, in the Inspector preview,
在工具窗口中,在检查员预览,
Just, I think it's the very top one, contentMode,
只是,我认为这是最顶端,内容模式,
All right, so I'm, I'm gonna be leaving the slides here so
好吧,我,我要离开这里的幻灯片
I will tell you what's coming up,
我将告诉你接下来会发生什么,
I'm gonna do this demo right now where I'm gonna do
现在我要做这个演示,我要做的
a custom view, a FaceView, a UIView that draws a face,
自定义视图,FaceView UIView,画了一个脸,
And then Wednesday, I'm gonna talk about gestures,
星期三,我要讲的手势,
We'll add some gestures to control our face,
我们将添加一些手势来控制我们的脸,
And I'm gonna start talking about multiple MVCs,
我要开始讨论多个mvc,
I'll finish up with multiple MVCs next week,
下周我将完成与多个mvc,
Your assignment three requires you to do multiple MVCs, so
作业三个需要你做多个mvc,
I'm not going to make it due until a week from next Monday,
我不打算把它从下周一到一个星期,
because you'll need next Monday's lecture,
因为你需要下周一的课,
However, I'll probably ship the assignment, the write-up,
但是,我可能会船作业,帐面价值,
on Wednesday, because a big part of that assignment
周三,因为很大一部分任务
is drawing your own custom view and you'll certainly know
画自己的自定义视图,你一定会知道吗
everything you need to know to do that right off the bat,
所有你需要知道的马上,
So you can kind of get started on the view, and
所以你可以在视图开始,和
then next Monday, you can start doing the multiple MVCs,
下周一,你可以开始做多个mvc,
And you'll still have a full week until the next Monday,
你仍然有一个完整的星期,直到下周一,
to get that done, alright,
完成,,好吧,
No Friday section this week,
本周星期五没有节,
Okay, so as with most demos in this course,
所以对于大多数演示在本课程中,
I'm going to start from scratch, okay,
我要从头开始,
We're going to do a completely new app,
我们要做一个全新的应用程序,
No more calculator in here,
在这里没有更多的计算器,
So I could click on here to open my calculator,
所以我可以点击这里打开计算器,
But instead, I'm gonna go back here to Create a new project,
但是相反,我会回到这里来创建一个新的项目,
Okay, it's gonna be Single View Application,
好吧,它会单一视图的应用程序,
as I told you they all would be,
我告诉你他们都是,
I'm gonna call this one FaceIt, okay,
我要叫这个FaceIt,好吧,
And it's gonna start out just drawing a face, but
它会一开始就画一个脸,但是
it's gonna do much more eventually,
它最终会做得更多,
And, still no core data or testing stuff yet, so
而且,仍然没有核心数据或测试的东西,所以
I'm just gonna do FaceIt here,
我只是要做FaceIt这里,
It's gonna say where do you want it?
它会说你想要在哪里?
I'm gonna put it in the same place the calculator is,
我要把它放在同一个地方计算器,
in my Developer,
在我的开发人员,
I'm not gonna be using SCM,
我不会使用SCM,
But of course,
当然,
those of you come who came to Friday section,
你来中那些来到周五部分,
you'll know how to use that,
你就会知道如何使用,
And here is my new app here,
这是我的新应用,
And I'm also going to do my standard thing,
我也要做我的标准,
where I'm gonna take these supporting files and
我要把这些支持文件在哪里
move them out of our way,
移动的方式,
So they don't distract us every time we look at
所以他们不使我们每次我们看
the Navigator here,
导航器,
Because we don't need those for this demo,
因为我们不需要那些对于这个演示,
So just like every other thing we've done, we have a view,
就像所有其他的事情我们做的,我们有一个观点,
Here's our story board with our view,
这是我们的故事与我们的观点,
Oops, not that small,
哦,不是小,
And of course, we have our controller,
当然,我们有我们的控制器,
And I'm gonna delete this out of the controller,
我要删除这个的控制器,
as usual here,
像往常一样,
And this time, we're going to start right off here
这一次,我们将从这里开始
by building a custom UIView, custom UIView subclass,
通过构建一个自定义UIView,定制UIView子类,
Now, the way we do that is the saw way we built
现在,我们做的是看到我们的建造方式
the CalculatorBrain,
的计算器大脑
We go here, new file, right,
我们去这里,新文件,
That's how we add new files to our project,
这就是我们添加新文件到我们的项目,
But this time, for
但是这一次,
CalculatorBrain we chose Swift File because it, you know,
迅速的计算器大脑我们选择文件,因为它,你知道,
it wasn't a UI thing,
它不是一个UI的事情,
It didn't inherit from any iOS class,
它没有继承任何iOS类,
But now we're gonna choose Cocoa Touch Class, because
但是现在我们要选择可可触摸类,因为
it's gonna be a subclass of a Cocoa Touch UIKit class,
它会Cocoa Touch UIKit类的子类,
So we click that,
我们点击,
It says, what do you want it to be a subclass of?
它说,你想要的一个子类?
And we want UIView, but you can see there's other things,
我们希望UIView,但是你可以看到有其他的事情,
UIViewController, and
ui,
other things that we'll learn later in the quarter,
其他的事情,我们将了解本季度晚些时候,
But this is a subclass of UIView,
但这是UIView的子类,
I'm gonna call it FaceView,
我要叫它FaceView,
because it's a view that draws a face,
因为这是一个观点,画了一个脸,
Okay, it's a good name,
好吧,这是一个好名字,
Alright, so we click here,
好的,所以我们点击这里,
It says, where do you wanna put it?
它说,你想把它放在哪里?
We usually wanna be very careful to put it in the same
我们通常想要非常小心地把它放在相同的
place as everything else is,
的地方,其他的都是
You don't want it in Supporting Files, and
你不希望它在支持文件,
you don't want it at this top level, the project level,
你不想让它在这个顶级,项目水平,
You want it inside this folder right here,
你想要在这个文件夹,
that has all your stuff in it,
有你所有的东西,
So we'll do that,
我们会这样做,
Alright, so here's our FaceView,
好的,这是我们的FaceView,
And you can see right off the bat in FaceView, we get this,
你可以看到在FaceView马上,我们得到了这个,
Which is our draw, okay, the draw with the rect,
这是我们画,画的矩形,
Notice that it is commented out,
注意,注释掉了,
And that's because for
这是因为
performance reasons, iOS doesn't want to ask views that
性能的原因,iOS不想问的观点
don't actually do any drawing, to draw,
实际上并不做任何绘画,画,
Because it has to keep a backing store for
因为它必须保持后备存储器
them, and there's memory stores and all this stuff,
,有记忆存储和所有这些东西,
So by default this comes commented out,
所以在默认情况下这是注释掉了,
But of course, our FaceView is going to draw,
当然,我们FaceView画,
It's going to draw a face,
它会画一个脸,
So we're going to un-comment it out,
所以我们要取消,注释
Okay, now we have a FaceView here,
好的,现在我们有一个FaceView这里,
it doesn't draw anything,
它不画任何东西,
But I actually wanna briefly go back to our storyboard, and
但实际上我想简要地回到我们的故事板,和
put a FaceView in the storyboard,
FaceView在故事板中,
And it's really simple but I want to show it to you,
非常简单,但我想告诉你,
if we go down to the Object Palette at the bottom here,
如果我们去对象面板底部,
And again,
再一次,
where we got our buttons and
我们得到了按钮和在哪里
labels, you know I could search here forever,
永远的标签,你知道我可以在这里搜索,
There's no FaceView in here,
这里没有FaceView,
But I can go down towards the bottom here, and
但我可以向底部,和
you will see this one,
你会看到这个,
It's actually almost at the very bottom, it's View,
其实几乎在最底部,它看来,
See, it represents a rectangular region which draws
看,它代表了一个绘制的矩形区域
and receives events, as promised,
正如所承诺的,接收事件
And so I can pick this guy up and drag him out,
所以我可以接这个家伙,把他拖出去,
Okay, and drop him here inside this view controller,
好吧,在这儿放他在这个视图控制器,
And remember that the top level view in this view
请记住,在这个视图的顶层视图
controller is a var called view,
控制器是一个var称为视图,
Okay, a very important var,
好吧,一个非常重要的变量,
Now, I want this view to fill the whole space,
现在,我想要这种观点填满整个空间,
So I'm actually gonna use the blue dash lines to
所以我要用蓝色虚线
make this thing fit the entire space, you see that?
使这个东西适合整个空间,你看到了吗?
Now, well, I also want to do the Ctrl-dragging to
现在,我也想做Ctrl-dragging
the edges that we did in calculator, remember that?
我们在计算器的边缘,还记得吗?
But it's actually kind of hard to do this because I want it
但实际上很难这样做,因为我想要它
all the way to the edges,
所有的边缘,
But since I used the blue lines, I can use a really cool
但自从我用蓝线,我可以使用一个很酷的
feature which is down here, this button,
功能下面,这个按钮,
You see this button in the lower right here?
你在这里看到这个按钮在右下角?
It says Resolve Auto Layout Issues,
解决自动布局问题,
If you click that,
如果你点击,
one of the choices is to Reset to Suggested Constraints,
其中一个选择是重置为建议的限制,
So that is the system saying, I'll make your constraints for
这就是系统说,我会让你的约束
you based on what you did with the blue lines,
你根据你的蓝线,
So I'm gonna look at your blue lines,
所以我要看看你的蓝线,
Since I used blue lines all at the edges,
因为我用蓝线所有的边缘,
if I say Reset to Suggested Constraints,
如果我说重置为建议约束,
it's gonna hook those things to the edges,
它会钩边那些东西,
Because that's what it looked I wanted,
因为这是我看起来想要什么,
Now I can double-check what it gave me by clicking here on
现在我可以仔细检查它给我点击这里
the Size Inspector,
尺寸检查器,
And if you look down towards the bottom of
如果你往下看的底部
the Size Inspector, you can see all your constraints,
尺寸检查器,你可以看到所有你的约束,
And look at that, perfect Trailing Space to Superview,
看看,完美的空间父视图之后,
leading space here,
领先的空间,
Excellent, all exactly what I want,
优秀的,正是我想要的,
So here, I've gotten all my Auto-Layout with one click,
这里,我已经通过一次点击自动布局,
And that's going to be possible to do quite a bit,
这将有可能相当多,
If you use those blue lines and
如果你使用这些蓝色的线条和
you say Reset to Suggested Constraints,
你说重置为建议约束,
often it'll at least get close,
通常它会至少接近,
And then you can kinda tweak the ones it didn't get right,
然后你可以调整它没有得到正确的,
Now, the other crucial thing I have to do here
现在,我必须做其他重要的事情
is that this is currently a UIView,
是,这是目前UIView,
If I go over here to this inspector here,
如果我到这里这个检查员,
which is the Identity Inspector, you can see that
标识符检查器,你可以看到了吗
the class of the selected thing is UIView,
选择的是UIView的类,
So no matter what I put in my draw,
所以无论我怎么把我的画,
it would never be called,
它永远不会被称为,
Because this is not a FaceView, it's a UIView,
因为这不是一个FaceView UIView,
But I can just click here, and go down and choose FaceView,
但我可以点击这里,选择FaceView,
And now I've made this a FaceView,
现在,我做了一个FaceView
all the code I put in my draw is going to draw in here,
我把我画的所有代码是画在这里,
So now,
现在,
And that's it,
就是这样,
that's all I need to do to put a custom view into my UI,
这就是我需要做进我的UI定制视图,
It's very common to want to put a custom view
很想把自定义视图
in, in the UI,
在UI中,
So that's why it's so simple to do,
这就是为什么它是如此简单,
Now all we need to do here is in our FaceView,
现在我们需要做的是在我们FaceView,
write the code that draws--draws our face,
写的代码——吸引了我们的脸,
So what are we gonna do to draw a face?
所以我们要做些什么来画一张脸吗?
Well, I'm just gonna draw the kind of emoji face, this round
我要画的那种emoji脸,这一轮
circle for a head, two round eyes, a little smile,
圆头,两个圆的眼睛,一个小微笑,
Okay, a very simple face,
好吧,一个非常简单的脸,
And, let's start by drawing the skull of our face, the,
,让我们开始画的骷髅的脸,,
kind of the head of this face,
的这张脸,
And I just start doing that in draw here,
我刚刚开始做,在这里画,
I'm going to use UIBezierPath to do all this,
我将使用UIBezierPath做这一切,
So I don't actually even need to get the context,
所以我甚至不需要上下文,
That UI get graphics, get context, don't even do that,
界面图形,得到背景,甚至不做,
Just use UIBezierPath automatically
只使用UIBezierPath自动
knows what context you're in,
知道你是在什么情况下,
So you don't have to do any of that,
所以你不需要做任何,
So what do I need to do though?
我需要做什么?
I need to kind of think of how big my face is,
我需要把我的脸有多大,
I want my face, if I'm in portrait or landscape, I also
我想让我的脸,如果我在横向或纵向,我也
want my face to kind of be the smaller of the two sides,
希望我的脸是双方的规模较小,
the height or the width,
高度或宽度,
You know what I mean?
你知道我的意思吗?
Because I always want the face to fully fit in there,
因为我总是要面对完全康复,
So I'm going to let my skullRadius, so that's gonna
所以我要让我的skullRadius,这就是会
be the radius of my skull, okay, equal the minimum,
是我的头骨的半径,等于最小值,
And there's this nice min,
这个最小值,
you see that min function right there?
你看,最小值函数?
It's generic-typed like an array,
generic-typed像一个数组,
Array of T, so that's the T,
一系列T,T,
It will take any type,
需要任何类型,
And it will compare two things, and
它会比较两个东西,
return the one that's the lowest,
返回最低的国家之一,
So I'm going to get the minimum of my bound,
我将得到我的最低,
bounds,size,width and my bounds,size,height,
范围、大小、宽度和范围,尺寸,高度,
And then I'm going to divide it by 2, because it's radius,
然后我要除以2,因为它的半径,
not diameter,
没有直径,
So now, see what I'm doing here?
现在,看到我在做什么吗?
I'm just making it so that my radius of my skull will be
我只是让它,这样我的头骨半径
smaller of the width or height,
小的宽度或高度,
And then, what about where I want the skull to be?
然后,我想要头骨呢?
Well, I want it to be right in the center,
好吧,我希望它是在中心,
So can I say, let skullCenter equal my center?
所以我能说,让skullCenter等于我的中心?
Okay, that's a method, can I say that?
好吧,这是一个方法,我能说吗?
That's a var, anything wrong with that?
这是一个var,什么错吗?
No, I see shaking heads--why not, what's wrong with that?
我看到有人摇头——为什么不呢,有什么问题吗?
Yeah?
是吗?
He says because it'll start from the top left,
他说,因为它会从左上角开始,
Not quite,
不大,
Anyone else wanna take a stab at this one?
任何人想要尝试这个吗?
It's because center, while it is the center of this view,
这是因为中心,虽然这种观点的中心,
it's in the wrong coordinate system,
它在错误的坐标系统,
This center is in my superview's coordinate system
这个中心在我父视图的坐标系统
and I'm in draw,
我在画画,
I need to be in my coordinate system,
我需要在我的坐标系统,
So there's actually two things I can do here,
这里有两件事我可以做,
One I could use this cool function in view called
我可以用这个很酷的功能视图
convert which will convert a point
转换将转化为一个点
from one coordinate system to another,
从一个坐标系统到另一个,
So I can go down to this one okay,
所以我可以去这一个好了,
convert CGPoint from view, and
从视图转换CGPoint,
I could convert this point center from my superview,
我可以把这个点中心从我父视图,
Okay, so just using center I can convert it,
好的,所以只是用中心我可以把它,
That would be fine, because I've converted it from one
这将是很好,因为我从一个转换
coordinate system, my superviews, to mine,
我父视图坐标系统,我的,
That's probably a little,
这可能是一点,
someone reading this code is like,
人就像阅读此代码,
hm, why are they doing that?
嗯,他们为什么要这样做呢?
A simpler way to do it is probably just to create
一个更简单的方法可能只是创造
a point, a CGPoint, that is my bounds midX, that's my
CGPoint一个点,那是我的界限midX,那是我的
middle X, see, that's a rect thing, and my bounds midY,
中间X,看,这是一个矩形的事情,和我的界限midY,
Okay,
好吧,
So I'm just creating the point that is the center,
我只是创造中心的点,
That makes sense?
这说得通吗?
much more straightforwardly there,
更直接,
All right, so now I have my radius and the center,
好,现在我有我的半径和中心,
Now I need to draw a circle,
现在我需要画一个圆,
So how do I draw a circle?
所以我怎样画一个圆?
I'm gonna do that with UIBezierPath,
我要做的,在UIBezierPath,
So I'm gonna say let path equal a UIBezierPath,
所以我想说让路径平等UIBezierPath,
Now, when we look at the constructors for
现在,当我们看的构造函数
UIBezierPath here you can see that we can draw an arc,
UIBezierPath在这里你可以看到,我们可以画一条弧线,
Which is actually what I'm going to use,
这是我要用什么,
We could draw an oval, which would be cool,
我们可以画一个椭圆形,很酷,
except the argument is a rect, and
除了参数是一个矩形
I have the center and the radius,
我的中心和半径,
So I can't, I don't really want to use oval,
所以我不能,我真的不想用椭圆形,
We could draw a rectangle,
我们可以画一个矩形,
I want a circle, so that's no good,
我想要一个圆,这样不好,
Or a rounded rect,
或一个圆角矩形,
I actually want the circle,
我真正想要的圆,
not a rectangle of any kind, okay?
没有任何一个矩形,好吗?
So I'm gonna use this one right here which draws an arc,
所以我要用这个画弧,
It just takes a center point and it draws a sweeping arc,
只是需要一个中心点和它做了一个全面的弧,
And I'm gonna draw this arc all the way around
我要画弧附近的所有道路
to make a circle, okay?
成一圈,好吗?
So how does that work?
那么这是怎么工作的呢?
Here, I'm gonna make some more space,
在这里,我要做一些更多的空间,
All right, so it wants to know the center of the arc,
好了,所以想知道弧的中心,
Well, that's my skull center, right?
好吧,这是我的头骨中心,对吧?
It wants to know the radius of the arc, well,
它想知道弧的半径,嗯,
that's my skullRadius, this easy,
这是我skullRadius,这个容易,
It wants to know the start angle,
它想知道一开始角度,
So that's the angle that it's gonna start sweeping,
这就是它会开始全面的角度,
I'm gonna choose 0,
我要选择0,
the angle 0 is straight out to your right,
角0是直接从你的权利,
Okay, so if you're looking at the screen,
好吧,如果你看着屏幕,
to the right straight across, that's 0,
直在右边,这是0,
And it's in radians,
的弧度,
how many people know what radians are to measure angle?
有多少人知道弧度测量角吗?
Okay most of you,
好吧你们大多数人,
So radians instead of degrees,
所以弧度而不是度,
we measure how much we're going up by radians,
我们测量多少弧度,
Radians go from zero all the way around to two pi,
弧度从0到2π,
Around the circle,
绕着圈,
Start at zero and then it will go around, pi over two,
从0开始,然后它会绕,π/ 2,
pi, you know, then pi is 180 degrees and
π,你知道,然后π是180度
then around to two pi is 360 degrees,
然后在2π是360度,
So it's in radians, so this end angle has to be in radians
所以弧度,这端角弧度
and I wanna go all the way around,
我想去,
So it's 2 times pi,
这是2乘以π,
We know that Double,pi is pi,
我们知道双,ππ,
And then clockwise is whether I'm gonna draw the arc around
然后顺时针是我要画弧
clockwise or the other way,
顺时针或其他方式,
It doesn't matter because I'm going all the way around to
没关系,因为我要去
get back to the start anyway,
回到一开始无论如何,
So I'll just say false,
所以我就说假,
There you go, counter-clockwise,
就这样,逆时针方向,
Now, I got a warning here, an error,
现在,我这里有一个警告,一个错误,
Let's look at that error,
让我们看看,错误,
What does it say, it says the binary operator* (and is
它说,它说二元运算符*(和是什么
pointing to this little multiplier right here) cannot
指着这个小乘数)不能
be applied to 'Int' and 'Double',
适用于“Int”和“双”,
Why is it saying that?
为什么说?
These arguments to UIBezierPath,
这些论点UIBezierPath,
the floating point arguments like a startAngle and
像startAngle浮点参数
endAngle, what type do you think it's supposed to be?
endAngle,你认为它应该是什么类型?
No one?
没有人吗?
I hear it being whispered, yes, CGFloat,
我听到它正在小声说,是的,CGFloat,
All drawing has to be CGFloat,
所有图纸必须CGFloat,
So is Double,pi, is that a CG float?
双,π,CG浮动吗?
No, it's a double,
不,这是一个双,
Is two a CGFloat?
两个是CGFloat吗?
Well it might be,
它可能是,
But Swift would have to infer that it's a CGFloat,
但斯威夫特必须推断CGFloat,
And right now Swift is confused about what that's
现在斯威夫特是困惑的
supposed to be because it knows this argument is
应该是,因为它知道这一观点
supposed to be a CGFloat, but
应该是一个CGFloat,但是
the thing you're multiplying it by is a Double,
你的东西把它乘以两倍,
So Swift doesn't know what to infer here,
这里迅速不知道来推断,
Doesn't know whether to refer that to as a Double or
不知道是否引用或两倍
a CGFloat,
CGFloat,
So the fix here, luckily, CGFloat has a pi,
所以这里的修复,幸运的是,CGFloatπ,
Just like double does,
就像双,
Now, everybody's happy, because Swift knows how to
现在,每个人都高兴,因为迅速知道如何
interpret this literal as a CGFloat,
解释这个文字CGFloat,
And this argument to the endAngle is now a CGFloat,
和这个论点endAngle现在是CGFloat,
So now everybody's happy,
现在每个人的快乐,
It's only complained that we don't use path yet,
只有抱怨我们不使用路径,
Okay?
好吧?
Excellent, so now we got this arc going all around,
优秀的,现在我们有这个弧周围,
Let's set something about the path like it's line width for
设的路径的线宽
example, we'll set a nice, fairly thick line,
例子中,我们将设置一个不错,相当粗线,
five points wide, that's what that means,
5分宽,这是什么意思,
five point zero, five points wide,
五点零,宽5分,
And then let's set the color,
然后我们设置的颜色,
So I'm gonna get UIColor, let's say, blue color and
所以我要得到用户界面颜色,比方说,蓝色
we'll say set, and by the way there's setFill and setStroke,
我们会说,顺便说一下有setFill setStroke,
There's also just set,
还有设置,
Set sets both the fill and the stroke,
组集填充和中风,
Here we only need to set the stroke color, but
在这里我们只需要设置描边颜色,但是
I'll just say set so that you learn about that one,
我就说,你了解,
And now I can just say path stroke okay and
现在我可以说中风好和道路
it's going to stroke that path,
它会中风,路径,
So let's see what this looks like,
让我们看看这是什么样子,
Let's go do iPhone 7 here,
让我们去做iPhone 7,
So hopefully this is gonna draw our skull,
希望这将会吸引我们的头骨,
There we go, a skull,
好了,一个头骨,
Whoo, first time, excellent,
哇,第一次,非常好,
Okay, now I don't like the look of that very
好的,现在我不太喜欢看的
much because it goes all the way to the edges and
因为它所有的边
with a thick line that's actually cut off a little bit,
粗线,实际上切断了一点,
So I want to move that in a little bit so we'll do that,
所以我想搬,我们会这样做,
Let's rotate and go from portrait to landscape,
让我们旋转,从画像景观,
Not good, not good,
不好,不好,
Okay, why is that happening?
好了,这是为什么发生?
That it's doing that,
它是这样做,
Well, that's that content
这就是内容
mode thing I was talking about, right?
模式我在说什么,对吧?
It's not calling my draw when it goes to this other
这不是叫我画的时候去了另一个
bound size right there, so it's just scaling the bits,
一定大小,所以只是扩展部分,
So let's fix both of those things,
让我们解决这些事情,
let's make it go in a little bit, and let's fix those bits,
让我们进去一点,让我们解决这些碎片,
To fix the bits, we're just gonna go back to our
修复,我们会回到我们的
storyboard, and click on our view right here,
故事板,点击我们的观点,
Lets get rid of this,
让摆脱这种,
Okay, click on our View, and go over to Utilities,
好,点击我们的观点,去公用事业、
Inspect this with the Attributes Inspector and look,
检查这个属性检查器和看,
the very first one, Content Mode, Scales to Fill,
第一,内容模式,尺度,
Every time the bounds change it's scales to bits to fill
每次边界改变它的尺度来填补
and we want Redraw,
我们需要重绘,
We could also probably use Center, but
可能我们也可以使用中心,但是
I actually want Redraw because if my bounds got smaller for
我真正想要的画,因为如果我的范围缩小了
example, I'd wanna draw my face smaller,
我想画我的脸小,
I wouldn't want to get cut off,
我不会想要切断,
Okay, so there's Redraw,
好的,有重绘,
That fixed that one, that was easy to fix,
固定的一个,很容易解决,
What about making this thing kinda smaller?
使这个东西有点小呢?
To do that, I'm actually gonna create a var called scale,
要做到这一点,我真的会创建一个名为规模的var,
And it's a drawing thing so it's a CGFloat,
这是一个画画的事情所以CGFloat,
And I'm going to set it to let's say 0,9 and
我要将它设置为0,9
that's going to mean 90%,
这将意味着90%,
All I'm going to do is take my radius and
我要做的就是把我的半径和
multiply it by that scale,
乘以规模,
So by multiplying my radius by 0,9 or
通过我的半径乘以0,9或
90% it should zoom move it in a little bit right,
90%应该放大移动它一点吧,
Kind of in from the edges by 90%,
从边缘的90%,
So let's see if both those things got fixed,
看看这两个东西有固定的,
So the 90% worked,
所以90%的工作,
Clearly, it's in 90% and the rotation works also,
显然,它在90%,旋转也工作,
So we're off to a good start here,
所以我们这里了一个好的开始,
things seem to be working just fine,
事情似乎工作得很好,
Alright, so, what's the next thing we wanna do?
好了,所以,接下来我们要做的是什么?
Well, we wanna draw eyes and
嗯,我们想画眼睛和
a mouth and things like that, I wanna start thinking
嘴之类的东西,我想开始思考
a little bit about my internal architecture,
一下我的内部架构,
And I'm kinda liking the idea of having some private funcs,
我有点喜欢的想法有一些私有函数,
like give me the path for the skull,
像给我头骨的路径,
And have that return a UIBezierPath that
并返回一个UIBezierPath
I can then stroke,
然后我可以中风,
And then I'll have the same thing, give me the path for
然后我也要一样的,给我的路径
the eye, give me a path for
的眼睛,给我一个路径
the mouth, you see what I mean?
嘴,你明白我的意思吗?
I'll get all these,
我将得到所有这些,
And so I can just take this code down here
所以我可以把下面这段代码
that creates this path for the skull and
头骨和创造这条道路
I'll just put it up here and I'll just return this path,
我会把它放在这里,我就返回这条路,
And then, down here, instead of saying paths,stroke,
然后,在这里,而不是说路径,中风,
I'll say pathForSkull(),stroke(),
我会说pathForSkull()、中风(),
Do you see that?
你看到了吗?
Now, another thing is the skullRadius and
现在,另一件是skullRadius和
the skullCenter, I want all the other things like the eyes
skullCenter,我希望所有的其他诸如眼睛
and the mouth to all be relative to that,
和嘴都是相对的,
So if I make my skull small I need the eyes to get smaller,
如果我让我的头骨小我需要眼睛变小,
the mouth to get smaller, everything to move in,
嘴巴小,一切都在移动,
So I'm gonna use these two guys,
所以我要用这两个家伙,
I'm gonna make them instead of being local variables in draw,
我要使他们在画而不是局部变量,
I'm gonna move them out and make them be private vars,
我要搬出来,让他们是私有的var,
And in specific they're gonna be private computed vars,
在特定的他们会是私有的var计算,
So I'm just gonna take what they were before and
所以我要把他们和之前
I'm just gonna return them so that no matter what my
我要归还,这样不管我什么
bounds is, at any given time, skullRadius,
在任何给定的时间,范围是skullRadius,
that var--which of course we have to type, so CGFloat--that
var,当然我们必须类型,所以CGFloat——
skullRadius is always going to match by bounds, okay?
skullRadius总是匹配范围,好吗?
Because every time I ask for it,
因为每次我问,
I'm gonna recompute it using this little function,
我要使用这个小函数,再计算它
And same thing with skullCenter,
并与skullCenter一样,
I'm gonna say private var skullCenter,
点击私人var skullCenter,
which is also a CGFloat, no this one is a CG point, and
也是一个CGFloat,没有这是一个重心点,然后呢
it's going to be computed,
这将是计算,
Now, one thing you noticed here,
现在,有一件事你注意到这里,
I don't remember if I covered this in the other lecture but
我不记得我是否在其他课但覆盖
you notice, I'm not saying get here,
你注意到,我并不是说,
See, I'm not putting get and set,
看,我不会给获取和设置,
Well, I'm not putting set because you can't set
好吧,我不是因为你不能集合
the skull center,
头骨中心,
Skull center is always the center of my bounds so
头骨中心总是我的边界的中心
I can't set it,
我不能把它,
And then if you have only a get,
如果你只有一个,
turns out you don't need the get,
你不需要得到,
Because it's kinda redundant,
因为它有点冗余,
So you get this kinda nicer looking code here,
得到这个更好看代码,
So now we have skullRadius and
现在我们有skullRadius和
skullCenter available to all of our methods,
skullCenter提供给我们所有的方法,
And so all our other paths, like path for eye and
所以我们所有的其他路径,如眼睛和路径
all that stuff can use them,
所有的东西可以使用它们,
So let's get started on those,
让我们开始,
Let's do path for eye, how about that,
让我们为眼睛做路径,如何,
So in a private func, pathForEye,
所以在一个私人func pathForEye
Now actually, probably the path for the eye
实际上,可能的路径
is almost the same for the left eye and the right eye,
几乎是同样的左眼和右眼,
So I'm gonna create a little type here called Eye which
所以我要创建一个名为眼睛的小类型
is just gonna be a little enum,
只是会有点枚举,
And it's gonna just be the left and right eye, so
和它会是左右眼,如此
private enum Eye,
私人enum的眼睛,
Let's see Eye is case left case right, okay,
看看眼睛离开案件是正确的,好的,
So I mean it's perfectly fine to use an enum
我的意思是,这绝对是很好的使用enum
just to represent something simple like this,
只是代表这样简单的东西,
You don't have to always be doing methods and
你不需要总是做方法和
associated values,
相关的值,
We don't have any associated values here,
我们没有任何关联的值,
We're just representing it as a way to specify in this API,
我们只是代表这个API来指定,
which eye we want the path, the UIBezierPath, for,
哪只眼睛我们希望的道路,UIBezierPath,,
So, by the way, also I wanna have some constants
顺便说一下,我也想有一些常数
that tell me where the eye is relative to the center and
告诉我,眼睛是相对于中心
where the mouth is and how big the eyes are,
嘴巴和眼睛是多大,
So to save a little bit of time here, I'm going to just
为了节省一点时间在这里,我要
type those in at the bottom here real quick,
类型的底部快速,
Look how fast I typed them in,
看我输入速度,
This is, by the way, how we do
顺便说一下,这是我们如何做
constants in swift we just create a struct and we make
常数迅速我们只是创建一个结构体
static lets on it which are all of our constants and
静态让我们所有的常量和
what's really cool about this, one it groups them together,
很酷的,一组在一起,
Like here I have Ratios,
像这里有比率,
it's all the ratios between the skull radius and all these
这都是头骨半径和所有这些之间的比率
things I want to do like the eye offset and the mouth,
我想做喜欢的事情抵消和嘴,
Also it types them,
也类型,
You see these are typed constants,
你看到这些类型的常量,
I can put the type in there, because they're just vars,
我可以把类型,因为他们只是var,
they're static vars on this struct,
它们是静态的var在这个结构体,
Okay, We don't have any storage
好吧,我们没有任何存储
in this struct,
在这个结构体,
Doesn't have any methods,
没有任何方法,
It just is only used for constants here,
它只是用于常数,
Now, I'm gonna use these constants down here, and
现在,我要用下面这些常数,
I'm gonna use the skull radius and
我要用半径和头骨
center up here to calculate the path for the eye,
中心在这里计算的路径,
So how am I gonna do that?
所以我要怎么做呢?
First I need the center of the eye,
首先我需要眼睛的中心,
Now, I'm gonna create a function to calculate
现在,我要创建一个函数来计算
the center of the eye,
眼睛的中心,
But I only need it for pathForEye,
但我只需要pathForEye,
So I'm actually gonna put it inside pathForEye,
所以我要把它pathForEye内部,
So I'm gonna create a function here, centerOfEye,
所以我要创建一个函数,centerOfEye,
Just gonna type it in quick here to save some time,
要类型快速来节省一些时间,
I'll go through it though,
不过,我要通过它
And centerOfEye, look how it's inside pathForEye,
pathForEye内和centerOfEye,看它是如何,
And that's perfectly legal, some of you are probably using
这是完全合法的,你们中的一些人可能使用
that strategy in your assignment two,
这一策略在作业两个,
I think I mentioned it in a hint, that you can do it,
我认为我提到的一个提示,你可以这样做,
And all it does is, it keeps centerOfEye inside here,
它所做的是,它使centerOfEye里面,
because it's not needed anywhere else,
因为它不需要别的地方,
So now, readers of my code don't have to worry about this
现在,我的代码的读者不必担心这个
thing being called somewhere else, and
东西被称为别处
what it's semantics might be out there,
可能存在的语义,
They already know that it's only used in this nice,
他们已经知道这只是用于这个不错,
little space right here, so it's kind of a nice way to
这里的小空间,所以这是一种很好的方式
arrange your code to make it a little more readable,
安排您的代码更可读,
So how does centerOfEye work?
所以centerOfEye是如何工作的呢?
Well it takes the eye, and
它的眼睛,
it just gets the eye offset by taking the skull radius and
它只是被眼睛所抵消半径和头骨
dividing it by one of those constants,
除以一个常数,
the ratio between the skull radius to the eye offset,
颅骨之间的比例半径补偿,
that's how much it's gonna offset the eye,
这就是它会抵消,
Now I'm gonna offset the eye the same amount up as I do
现在我要弥补眼睛相同数量和我一样
to the sides,
国,
So the line between the nose of our face, and
所以我们的脸,鼻子之间的界线
the two eyes is gonna be equilateral triangles, or no,
两只眼睛是等边三角形,或者不,
not quite equilaterals,
不等边三角形,
It can be a little wider, but
这可能有点大,但是
the same distance going up as it is going out to the sides,
相同的距离上升去边,
I'm gonna start with the eyeCenter being in the center,
我要开始eyeCenter中心,
And then,
然后,
I'm starting with the eye in the center of the face, and
我从眼睛中心的脸,和
then I'm gonna move it up and over,
然后我要移动它,
Okay, So here I'm moving it up,
好吧,这里我移动它,
Notice that up is minus the eye offset,
注意,是-眼睛抵消,
because decreasing y is up, increasing y is down,
因为减少y,y是增加了,
And for x, I'm going to add the eye offset or
x,我要添加眼睛抵消或
subtract the eye offset,
减去偏移,
depending on whether it's the left eye or the right eye,
这取决于它的左眼或右眼,
So for the left eye, I'm going to subtract the eye offset,
我的左眼,减去偏移,
And for the right eye, I'm going to add the eye offset,
右眼,我要添加眼睛抵消,
Okay?
好吧?
Everyone understand that little
每个人都明白,小
construct right there, I hope,
构造,我希望,
Okay and then it's returning the center,
好吧,然后返回中心
So now I have the center of the eye,
所以现在我有眼睛的中心,
So using the center of the eye,
所以使用眼睛的中心,
I can say let the eye radius equal the skull radius
我能说让眼睛半径半径相等的头骨
divided by the ratio for that one,
除以1的比例,
which is skullRadiusToEyeRadius,
skullRadiusToEyeRadius,
Okay, so that's what I'm gonna do,
好了,这就是我要做的,
And I'm gonna let the eyeCenter just
我要让eyeCenter而已
equal centerOfEye, whichever eye,
等于centerOfEye,哪个眼睛,
The eye that's up here,
的眼睛,
So I'm just calling this little function right here,
我只是调用这个函数,
And so I have those two things,
所以我这两件事,
So I can just create another circle,
所以我可以创建另一个圆,
So I'm going to let path equal UIBezierPath and
所以我要让平等UIBezierPath和道路
do that arc again,
再次做弧,
Here the center is the eye center,
这里的中心是眼科中心,
And the radius is the eye radius,
半径,半径是眼睛,
And the start angle is still zero,
和角仍然是零开始,
Then end angle is still CGFloat,pi* 2, and clockwise,
然后结束角仍CGFloat,π* 2,顺时针,
it doesn't matter,
没关系,
I'll go the other way this time,
这次我去另一个方向,
Okay, so there's my path,
好,这是我的路,
Let's set path,lineWidth equal 5,0 again,
设路径线宽= 5 0,
Starting to get tired of typing that,
开始厌倦了打字,
It's probably not a good thing,
它可能不是一件好事,
And then let's return the path,
然后我们返回的路径,
Okay, So that's it,
好吧,就是这样,
So that gets the path for either the left eye or
所以让左眼或的路径
the right eye,
右眼,
we'll say pathForEye, the left eye, stroke,
我们会说pathForEye,左眼,中风,
Okay, pathForEye, the right eye, stroke,
好的,pathForEye,右眼,中风,
Okay, I hope everyone's comfortable with the fact that
好的,我希望每个人都熟悉这一事实
I'm calling a method, taking this return value, and
我打电话是一个方法,把这个返回值,
immediately sending it a message,
立即发送一个消息,
So, let's see how this went,
所以,让我们来看看这个,
Let's see if we got this right,
看看我们有这个权利,
Look at that,
看,
FIrst time,
第一次,
It's really going well today,
今天很顺利,
Okay, so there's our two lines, they look good,
好,这是我们的两条线,他们看起来不错,
You know what would be kind of cool though?
你知道会很酷吗?
If we could have open eyes and closed eyes,
如果我们可以睁开眼睛,闭上眼睛,
So how could we, how could we have open eyes and
所以我们如何,我们怎么能有眼睛和开放
How about this: let's go up here and just like we had this
这个怎么样:走吧,就像这个吗
closed eyes?
闭上眼睛吗?
var scale which by the way notice I left the var public,
var规模,顺便通知我离开了var公共,
Scale, so that people who are using my face view,
规模,这样的人使用我的脸看来,
they can control the size of the face,
他们可以控制的大小脸,
I don't mind,
我不介意,
And, I'm also gonna have eyes open, which is going to be
我也要睁大眼睛,这将是
a bool, which will start out being false,
bool,一开始是假的,
And we're just gonna make our pathForEye,
我们要让我们的pathForEye,
look at this var, look at the value of this var,
看看这个变量,这个变量的值,
And either have the eyes open or closed,
和眼睛开放或关闭,
So, I'm back here in path for eye,
所以,我回到这里在路径,
So, if the eyes are open then we're just gonna do what we
所以,如果眼睛是打开之后我们要做什么
were already doing here, this business,
已经在这里干什么,这个业务,
Okay, because that's what we did so far,
好吧,因为这是我们到目前为止,
But if the eyes are closed,
但是如果眼睛是封闭的,
then I want the path to be different,
然后我想要的路径不同,
So, watch what I'm gonna do here,
所以,看我要做什么,
Let path be a UIBezierPath without a value to start,
让道路成为没有价值的UIBezierPath开始,
Okay, and then I set it here, and I'm gonna set it here, and
好吧,然后我把它在这里,我将把它在这里,
that's allowed,
这是允许的,
In other words Swift is smart enough to know,
换句话说斯威夫特是足够聪明知道,
you created a let, which can only be initialized once,
你创造了一个让,只被初始化一次,
But you conditionally initialized it here,
但是你有条件地初始化,
because now I'm gonna say path equals,
因为现在我要等于说路径,
And for the closed case I'm just gonna make
和封闭的情况下我要做
a bezier path that starts out blank,
贝塞尔曲线路径,开始一片空白,
And then I'm gonna just move to, line to,
然后我要搬到,行,
to make a little horizontal line for a closed eye,
为一个封闭的一个水平线,
So, I'm gonna say path,move(to: ) to move to
所以,点击路径,移动:移动到
a point, CGPoint, we use this constructor right here,
CGPoint一点,我们使用这个构造函数,
Not that one, let's use, this one, CGFloat,
不是一个,让我们用这个,CGFloat,
And the point we're gonna move to we're gonna move to
关键我们要搬到我们要搬到
the eyeCenter x minus the eyeRadius,
eyeRadius eyeCenter x -,
So, we're gonna move to the center of the eye and
所以,我们要搬到眼睛的中心
back up with the eye there,
备份的眼睛,
And we're gonna be at the eyeCenter,y,
我们会在eyeCenter,y,
So, we're gonna right in the eyeCenter and
所以,我们要正确的eyeCenter和
we're gonna draw a horizontal line so
我们要画一条水平线
we're gonna move to the left side of it,
我们要搬到左边,
And then we're going to add a line to the right side,
然后我们向右侧添加一行,
So, another CGPoint which is this one again,
所以,另一个CGPoint,再次是这个,
And this one is going to be the eyeCenter,x
这一个是eyeCenter,x
plus the eyeRadius,
加上eyeRadius,
And it's still at the eyeCenter, okay?
它仍然是在eyeCenter,好吗?
Make sense?
有意义吗?
Two more parentheses in there,
两个括号,
Everyone see what I did there?
每个人都明白我在做什么?
But I just wanna make sure you understood this
我只是想确保你明白这一点
thing of let path,
的路径,
You don't have to say equals here as long as this if then
你不必说等于只要这如果
still only initializes it once and doesn't change it,
仍然只初始化一次,不会改变,
Because it's still a valid let,
因为它仍然是一个有效的让,
So, let's go take a look at that,
所以,让我们去看一看,
Okay, eyes closed,
好吧,闭上眼睛,
Excellent, okay?
好的,好吗?
They're closed eyes,
他们闭上眼睛,
We can go back here, set this to true,
我们可以回到这里,设置为true,
And again, we should get open eyes,
再一次,我们应该睁开眼睛,
Questions?
问题吗?
So, the question is when do people do a custom
所以,问题是当人们做一个定制的
view like this when they draw off their own thing?
这样的观点当他们脱去自己的事呢?
In other words, when they don't use this built in things
换句话说,当他们不使用这个事情造成的
like button and things like that well it depends on
喜欢按钮之类的,这取决于
the content that they are providing,
他们提供的内容,
But a lot of times, maybe they are not drawing with arcs and
但是很多时候,也许他们并不与弧和绘图
circles, maybe they're drawing with images and text okay?
圈,也许他们是绘画与图像和文本?
They're laying how they want down to a level or
他们将如何他们想要或水平
in an orientation that those can do or maybe they're doing
在一个方向,那些能做或者他们在做什么
text along a curve, which you can do with this for example,
文本沿着曲线,例如,你可以用这个
So, it's that kind of thing,
所以,这样的事情,
You might not see raw drawing like this,
你可能不会看到这样的原始图,
We're doing raw drawing because it's simple and
我们做的原始图,因为它很简单和
I'm trying to show you how you do it,
我想告诉你怎么做,
But there are apps that are drawing
但也有图的应用
apps where you can take your finger and draw,
应用程序,你可以把你的手指,画,
They would clearly do this as well right,
他们也清楚这样做对的,
some of you might do that as your final project,
你们中的一些人可能会做期末项目,
Okay, so anyway there's our eye,
好的,总之我们的眼睛,
So, we've got our eyes going, we've got our skull,
所以,我们有我们的眼睛,我们有我们的头骨,
How about our mouth?
我们的嘴呢?
We've gotta get the mouth going so let's go do that,
我们得嘴让我们这样去做,
And we're gonna do the same thing there,
我们要做同样的事情,
I'm gonna have a private func pathForMouth and
我要有一个私人func pathForMouth和
it's gonna be a UIBezierPath,
它会是一个UIBezierPath,
So, how I'm going to do the mouth,
所以,我要怎么做,
Actually, I'm going to start by drawing the mouth as
实际上,我要先画嘴巴
a rectangle,
a长方形,
just to show you where I'm gonna put it on screen,
只是为了告诉你,我要把它放在屏幕上,
And then we'll turn it, we'll use a bezier curve,
然后我们会把它,我们将使用贝塞尔曲线,
actually, to make the mouth,
实际上,嘴,
So, how am I going to do that?
所以,我要怎么做呢?
First, I'm going to calculate
首先,我要计算
some things like the width of the mouth, the height of
有些东西像口的宽度,高度的
the mouth, and the offset of the mouth--the offset down
嘴巴,嘴巴的抵消——抵消
from the middle of the face--using more of these
从中间的脸上,使用更多的
ratios,
比率,
So, I'm just calculating the mouth, width,
所以,我只是计算的嘴,宽度,
height, and offset,
高度,和偏移量,
Now, I'm gonna use that to create the rectangle in which
现在,我要用它来创建的矩形
I'm going to put the mouth,
我要把嘴,
Let's do that, let mouthRect equal and so the mouthRect
我们这样做,所以mouthRect mouthRect平等
is gotta be offset down by the mouth offset,
要抵消的嘴巴抵消,
And it's gonna be the width and height, so let's do that,
和它的宽度和高度,让我们来做,
So, CGRect we'll use this constructor right here,
所以,CGRect中我们将使用这个构造函数,
CGFloat, we'll do the skull's center dot x
CGFloat,我们会做点x头骨的中心
minus the mouth's width, divided by two,
-口的宽度,除以2,
So that's, because we obviously want the mouth
这是,因为我们显然希望的嘴
centered in there, and then for y,
集中在那里,然后y,
we'll use the skullCenter,y plus the mouthOffset,
我们将使用skullCenter,y + mouthOffset,
And again it's plus,
再加上,
because plus is down in our drawing system,
因为加在我们的绘图系统,
And the width is just the mouthWidth and
和宽度只是mouthWidth和
the height is the mouthHeight,
高度是mouthHeight,
Let me make this a little easier to read like this,
让我把这一点更容易阅读,
Everyone understand what I'm
每个人都明白我
doing there with the mouse rect?
用鼠标有矩形干什么?
Let's just draw this rect,
让我们画矩形,
So, I can say let path equal UIBezierPath,
所以,我可以说等于UIBezierPath让路径,
BezierPath knows how do a rect,
BezierPath知道如何做一个矩形,
It's this one down here,
它是下面这个,
The rect is our mouthRect and let's just return that path,
矩形是我们mouthRect我们返回路径,
So, now we've got a path for the mouth,
所以,现在我们有一个路径,
Let's go down here and
我们去这里
stroke it by saying pathForMouth(),stroke(),
中风是pathForMouth()、中风(),
Let's see what this looks like,
让我们看看这样子,
Okay, excellent,
好的,优秀的,
So, we have a mouth,
所以,我们有一个嘴巴,
Kinda looks like a robot face,
有点像机器人的脸,
We want it to have a nice curve, a smile or a frown,
我们想要有一个漂亮的曲线,一个微笑或皱眉,
So, we gotta start thinking a little bit how we're gonna
所以,我们要开始思考我们如何一点
represent whether this is smiling or frowning,
代表这是否是微笑或皱眉,
And so I'm gonna introduce another var, up at the top,
所以我要介绍另一个var,顶部,
here, just like I have it with the eyes are open,
在这里,就像我的眼睛是睁着的,
I'm gonna have a var which I'm gonna call mouthCurvature and
我要有一个我要叫mouthCurvature var
make it be a Double,
使它成为一个双,
I'll set it to, let's say 1,0 and
我会将它设置为,假设1,0
the semantics of this I'm going to have it be that
我要它的语义
1,0 is full smile and minus 1,0 is full frown,
1,0充满微笑和- 1,0充满皱眉,
And this is going to be public and this is going to be
这将是公开的,这将是
the public API that someone uses when they want to use my
有人使用的公共API时,想用我的
FaceView to tell me how much this mouth should be smiling,
FaceView告诉我多少这口应该微笑,
Okay, the mouth curvature right here,
好吧,嘴弯曲,
And I've just defined it this way,
我刚刚这样定义,
It's public, I've documented it,
这是公共,我记录它,
And so people can set it to whatever they want,
所以人们可以设置为任何他们想要的,
So I'm going to use this now to do it,
现在我要用这个,
Now one thing is I've defined it as a double because,
现在有一件事是我将它定义为一个双,因为
you know I'm not actually doing the drawing right now
你知道我现在没有做画
I'm just talking conceptually what curvature is,
我只是在概念上曲率是什么,
So, I need to convert this in the some meaningful CGFloat,
所以,我需要把一些有意义的CGFloat,
and then use that to draw this mouth,
然后用它来画这口,
So, how am I gonna do that?
所以,我要怎么做呢?
The way I'm gonna do that do that is let's get this back up
我要做的,就是让我们得到这个备份
here and I'll show you, on the rectangle that we have here,
在这里,我将向您展示,在我们这里的矩形,
I'm gonna use what's called a Bezier curve,
我要用所谓的贝塞尔曲线,
how many people know what is Bezier curve is?
有多少人知道是贝塞尔曲线是什么吗?
Only one person!
只有一个人!
My Gosh, okay so a Bezier curve is just
天哪,好是贝塞尔曲线
two end points a line between two end points but
两个端点在两个端点之间绘制一条线
there are two other points called control points,
还有两个点称为控制点,
And you can kinda think it as,
你可以认为这有点,
think of it as the line starts out at the start,
把它看作线从一开始,开始
starts heading for one of the control points,
开始走向一个控制点,
As it gets close, it starts heading for the other one,
当它接近,走向另一个开始,
And as it gets close to that one, it starts heading for
当它接近,它开始走向
the end, okay,
最后,好的,
So, the control points kind of pull on the line and
所以,控制点的线和拉
give it some curve,
给它一些曲线,
And you can put those control points anywhere you want,
你可以把这些控制点任何你想要的,
Obviously, we're gonna put ours like this,
很明显,我们要把我们像这样,
So, my start is gonna be right here in the middle of this
所以,我开始会在这
line and my end is gonna be right here,
线,我是在这里,
So we're gonna draw a line across here,
所以我们要在这里画一条线,
And my two control points are going to
和我的两个控制点
be down here somewhere, on both sides of his chin,
下面是某个地方,两边的下巴,
the line is gonna start here, start down towards this one,
线会从这里开始,开始对这一个,
And so
所以
Whoop, Starting going to
将会开始大叫
the other one,
另一个,
Whoop, Come back up here, And make a little smile,
大叫,回来这里,做一个微笑,
And if I move my control points up to
如果我移动我的控制点
the top, then whoop,
顶部,然后大叫,
It'll be a frown,
这将是一个皱眉,
Everyone understand that,
每个人都明白,
So I need four points,
所以我需要4分,
The start, the end, and the two control points,
一开始,结束,两个控制点,
Let's do those,
让我们做这些,
The start is easy,
一开始是很容易的,
that's just the middle of the left edge, okay,
这就是左边缘的中间,好吧,
So I can say the start is CGPoint,
所以我可以说一开始是CGPoint,
And again we'll do this kind of CGPoint,
我们会做这种CGPoint,
And it's going to be the mouth rect, our little mouth rect,
口的矩形,我们的小口矩形,
MinX, that's the left edge, the minimum X, and
风骚女子,左边缘,最小X,
mouthRect,midY, that's halfway up the mouth rect,
midY mouthRect,半腰口矩形,
And the end is going to be CGPoint,
最后是CGPoint,
This float,
这个浮动,
And this one's gonna be the mouthrect,maxX and
这人会是mouthrect,maxX的和
mouthrect,midY on the other side,
mouthrect midY,另一方面,
So the two ends, start and end,
所以两端,开始和结束,
are right in the middle of my mouth rect on either side,
就在我口中的中间矩形的两边,
So now I need those two control points,
所以现在我需要这两个控制点,
For the control points I need to think of how far down
我需要考虑的控制点多远
they're going to be,
他们会,
And it depends on the mouth curvature,
这取决于口曲率,
The more smile I want, the farther down they need to be,
微笑我想越远,他们需要,
The more frown I want, the farther up they need to be,
我想越皱眉,他们需要越远,
So I'm gonna create another thing called smileOffset,
所以我要创建另一个名为smileOffset,
And this is gonna be a CGFloat, because it's gonna be
这将是一个CGFloat,因为它会
something that I'm using to do drawing here,
我使用的东西做图,
And I'm gonna make it equal to the mouthCurvature,
我要让它等于mouthCurvature,
which is a double, times the mouth rect,height,
这是一个双,乘以口矩形,高度,
So I will move down those control points all the way
所以我将这些控制点
the entire height of a mouth rect if I'm fully smiling,
整个嘴矩形的高度如果我完全微笑,
Now, there's some problems with this line of code,
现在,有一些问题这行代码,
One is, if you look at these things right here,
一个是,如果你看看这些东西在这里,
it's saying you can't multiply a Double times a Float,
这是说你不能双重乘以一个浮点数,
This is a float, this is a double,
这是一个浮点数,这是一个双,
So I'm gonna have to convert this to a float
所以我必须转换为一个浮点数
by using a constructor for CGFloat,
CGFloat通过使用一个构造函数,
Luckily, it has one that takes a double okay,
幸运的是,它有一个,两个好了,
Another thing here is smile offset has to be between,
另一件事是抵消之间必须是微笑,
you know, one, or sorry,
你知道,,抱歉,
mouth curvature here has to be between one and minus one,
口曲率有1到- 1,
So I'm gonna enforce that,
所以我要执行,
Because I wouldn't want this path curvature to be five, and
因为我不会想要这条道路曲率5、和
now he's smiling so
现在他的微笑
big that it's, you know, on the floor literally,
大的,你知道,在地板上,
Jaws on the floor,
大白鲨在地板上,
We don't want that,
我们不希望这样,
So I'm going to use min and max to do that,
所以我要使用min和max,
I'm gonna say max minus one of min
我说马克斯- 1分钟
of the mouth curvature and one,
口曲率和一个,
And that's going to restrict it to be between minus one
这将限制- 1之间
and one,
还有一个,
Everybody got that,
大家都明白了,
I'm just using min and max to do that there,
我只是使用min和max这样做,
And notice that it's automatically
注意,它自动
made these be doubles, which is fine,
这是双打,很好,
So the result of min and max is double, and
最小和最大的结果是双,和
that's being converted to a CGFloat,
被转换为CGFloat,
That works fine,
这工作好,
Okay, so now that I have that smile offset,
好的,现在,我有微笑抵消,
I can say how far down my control points are,
我能说我的控制点,有多远
So I'm gonna let cp1, which is control point one, it's gonna
所以我要让cp1,控制点,它会
be smile offset times the mouth rect height down,
微笑抵消倍口矩形的高度,
And I'm gonna make the two control points be
我要两个控制点
one third of the way in from the edges of the mouth rect,
三分之一的方式从口边缘的矩形,
Does that make sense?
这说得通吗?
We wanted to kinda head down, we wanted to kinda
我们想要有点低着头,我们想有点
be one-third of the way along from each side,
有三分之一的沿着从每个方面,
So cp1 is gonna be on the left,
所以cp1会在左边,
That's gonna be a CGPoint,
会有CGPoint,
And this again,
这再一次,
And so this one will be the start,x,
这人会开始,x,
Start is where we're starting right here,
开始,我们从这里开始,
Plus the mouthRect,width divided by three,
加上mouthRect,宽度除以三,
So I'm going a third of the way across,
所以我要穿越的三分之一,
And then the y is a start,y plus the smile offset
然后是y是一个开始,y +微笑抵消
which could be negative if mouth curvature is negative,
这可能是-如果口曲率是负的,
Smile offset might be negative, meaning going up,
微笑抵消可能是负的,意味着上升,
And so, this will be a frown,
所以,这将是一个皱眉,
Or it could be positive and then it will go down,
也可以是积极的,然后它会下降,
Then cp2 is almost exactly the same so I'll copy and
然后cp2几乎是一模一样的复制和
paste it, cp2,
paste it,二年级,
It's just that here we're gonna go to the end and
只是我们要去结束
move back by mouthRect,width,
由mouthRect向后移动,宽度,
But it's still it's at the same level okay because we
但它仍然是好的,因为我们是在同一水平
want it to come down, go across, and then come back up,
想要下来,穿过,然后回来,
So now that we have these control points and
现在我们有这些控制点和
the start and the end, now we can draw that in the path,
开始和结束,现在我们可以画的路径,
So we'll just do go our Bézier path right here,
所以我们就做我们的贝塞尔曲线路径,
We'll leave the rect in there at first so we can see it,
我们先离开矩形在那里我们可以看到它,
And I'm just gonna tell the path to move to a CGPoint,
我要告诉CGPoint路径移动,
which is the start and, actually,
这是开始,实际上,
you don't even need to do that,
你甚至不需要这样做,
You just say, move to the start,
你只是说,一开始,
And then, we're gonna draw a curve, addCurve,
然后,我们要画一条曲线,addCurve,
which adds one of the Bezier curves,
增加一个贝塞尔曲线,
And we're going to the end,
我们要结束,
And the control point is cp1, and the other is cp2,
cp1的控制点,另一个是cp2,
So let's take a look,
让我们来看一看,
Alright, excellent, so we have mouth curvature is 1,0,
好的,优秀的,所以我们有口曲率是1,0,
we've got a nice big old smile,
我们有一个漂亮的老微笑,
Okay, we don't really want this square there anymore,
好吧,我们真的不希望这广场了,
rectangle, so we'll get rid of that,
矩形,所以我们去掉,
We can just do that by creating an empty Bezier
我们可以通过创建一个空的贝塞尔曲线
curve to start,
曲线开始,
Also, we want the path's lineWidth to be 5,0,
同时,我们希望路径的线宽是5,0,
One nice, even amount,
一个很好的,即使数量,
And let's go ahead and check some other things,
让我们去检查一些其他的事情,
Let's see if the mouth of minus 0,5,
看看- 0的嘴,5,
Let's see if that gives us a slight frown,
看看,给了我们一个轻微的皱眉,
Should give us a slight frown, right,
应该给我们一个轻微地皱着眉头,
Neat, okay,
整洁的,
Alright, what's the last thing I'm gonna show,
好了,我要展示的最后一件事,
One thing that's a little bit of a pain is
一件事有点疼痛
every time I wanna check the mouthCurvature,
每次我想检查mouthCurvature,
I gotta go run the app,
我要去运行程序,
Back, change it, run,
回来,改变它,,
Or every time eyes open, eyes closed,
或每次睁大眼睛,闭上眼睛,
Back and forth,
来来回回,
in Interface Builder, okay?
在界面构建器,好吗?
I can see a button
我可以看到一个按钮
when I change it's things in Interface Builder,
当我在Interface Builder中改变它的东西,
And wouldn't it even be cooler if I could have an inspector
它甚至会不会冷,如果我可以有一个检查员
in Interface Builder,
在界面构建器,
that would let me inspect these things,
这将让我检查这些东西,
Well, of course we can do that,
当然我们能做到这一点,
How do we do that,
我们如何做到这一点,
We go up here, and we just make this IBDesignable, okay,
我们去这里,我们只是让这个IBDesignable,好吧,
If you put IBDesignable in front of a UIView at the top,
如果你把IBDesignable UIView前在顶部,
then when you go over to your storyboard, at the top, you're
当你去你的故事板,在顶部,你
gonna see it here, compiling that code, integrating it into
会看到这里,编译这段代码,将它集成到
Interface Builder, and showing it to you,
界面构建器,展示给你,
Okay now unfortunately we don't have an inspector here
现在不幸的是我们没有一个检查员
that allows us to inspect those things,
让我们检查这些东西,
But we can do that as well,
但是我们也可以这样做,
Go back to FaceView here,
回到FaceView这里,
And I'm going to say for
和我说
example make the scale IBInspectable,
例子让IBInspectable规模,
Let's make eyesOpen IBInspectable,
让我们把eyesOpen IBInspectable,
Let's make the mouthCurvature IBInspectable,
让我们使mouthCurvature IBInspectable,
Let's add a few other things here,
让我们添加一些其他的事情,
Let's make the lineWidth IB inspectable,
让我们使谱线宽度IB inspectable,
So to do that, we can't have this 5,0 going on over here,
所以要做到这一点,我们不能有这样的5 0在这里,
we're gonna have to add a var,
我们需要添加一个var,
So we're just gonna add an IBInspectable var,
所以我们要添加一个IBInspectable var,
Which is gonna be the line width, which is a CGFloat,
这是线宽,这是一个CGFloat,
We'll start it out at 5,0 but we'll be able to change it,
我们会在5 0,但我们可以改变它,
So now we can go everywhere where we have that 5,0,
现在我们可以到处都有,5 0,
We'll just change it to use this var,
我们只要改变它使用这个变量,
We can also do the color,
我们也可以做的颜色,
IBInspectable var the color, it's a UI color,
IBInspectable var的颜色,这是一个用户界面的颜色,
Okay, we'll start it out as blue like it is now,
好的,我们将开始它是蓝色的和现在一样,
So where we have view UIColor,blue,
所以我们认为用户界面颜色,蓝色,
we'll use this var instead,
我们将使用此var相反,
Alright, we'll give you a color blue,
好的,我们会给你一个蓝色,
I'm just gonna say color, to set the color,
我只是想说颜色,设置颜色,
Okay, so basically it's taking all the things in my app and
好的,基本上把所有的事情在我的应用程序
just making them not only configurable,
只是让他们不仅可配置的,
as public variables, but also inspectable,
作为公共变量,而且inspectable,
So let's go back to our story board and see if this works,
让我们回到我们的故事板,看看这个工作,
Sure enough, right away, you see up at the top there,
果然,马上,你看到在那里,
Face View, the scale, whether the eyes are open, line width,
面来看,规模,眼睛是否开放,线宽,
the color, mouth curvature, are now inspectable,
颜色,嘴巴曲率,现在inspectable,
So let's close the eyes,
让我们闭上眼睛,
Let's have the mouth curvature be 0,5,
让我们口曲率是0,5,
Let's make the color be orange,
我们做的颜色是橙色,
Let's make the line width be two,
让我们使谱线宽度是两个,
Let's make the scale be 0,5,
让我们做规模是0、5、
Make the scale be 0,9 again, whatever,
范围是0,9,无论如何,
Now another interesting thing about this is just like if you
现在另一个有趣的事就像如果你
were inspecting a UIButton here,
检查UIButton这里,
When you run it's going to use
当您运行的使用
these settings as the initial settings,
这些设置作为初始设置,
You truly are editing this,
你真的正在编辑,
just like you would edit anything else,
就像编辑,
any other custom view, see it comes up like this,
其他自定义视图,看到这样的出现,
Got it?
明白了吗?
Now one thing that you have to do when you have
现在你要做的一件事当你
an IBInspectable is you have to explicitly type you cannot
一个IBInspectable是你不能你必须显式类型
let Swift infer it,
我们迅速推断,
Because while Swift can infer, Interface builder cannot,
因为虽然斯威夫特可以推断,界面构建器不能,
It doesn't have an inference engine there,
它没有一个推理引擎,
So always make sure you put the actual type
所以总是确保你把实际的类型
in all the IBInspectables,
在所有IBInspectables,
Alright, that's it!
好了,这就是它!
what we're gonna do is we're gonna add a model to our MVC,
我们要做的是我们要添加一个对我们的MVC模型,
Next time,
下一次,
And we're gonna start putting some gestures in here,
在这里,我们将开始把一些手势,
And then we'll start talking about multiple MVCs,
然后我们开始讨论多个mvc,
>> For more, please visit us at stanford,edu,
> >更多内容,请访问我们的斯坦福大学edu,